<root>
<itemType>ItemType</itemType><name>Name (EN)</name><desc>Description (EN)</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shaved</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Receding</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Short</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Swept Back</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Ponytail</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wild</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Parted Center</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Semi-Long</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Curly</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Bobbed</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 11</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 12</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 13</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 14</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 15</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 16</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 17</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 18</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 19</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Male 20</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shaved</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Very Short</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wave</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Straight A</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Straight B</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Ponytail A</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Ponytail B</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Pigtails</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Bun</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Braided</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 11</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 12</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 13</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 14</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 15</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 16</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 17</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 18</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 19</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Female 20</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Travel Hairstyle</name>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Catarina</name> Helm</name><desc>"Distinctively shaped helm worn by the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>. Outside <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>, it is often ridiculed for its onion-like shape, infuriating the proud knights, but the masterfully forged curved design makes it very effective for parrying."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Catarina</name> Armor</name><desc>"Distinctively shaped armor worn by the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>. Outside <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>, it is often ridiculed for its onion-like shape, infuriating the proud knights, but the masterfully forged curved design makes it very effective for parrying."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Catarina</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Distinctively shaped gauntlets worn by the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>. Outside <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>, they are often ridiculed for their onion-like shape, infuriating the proud knights, but the masterfully forged curved design makes it very effective for parrying."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Catarina</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Distinctively shaped leggings worn by the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>. Outside <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>, they are often ridiculed for their onion-like shape, infuriating the proud knights, but the masterfully forged curved design makes it very effective for parrying."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name>, <name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> of the Catacombs. Long ago, <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> produced its first Undead, a paladin in golden armor. With the legendary treasures <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> and <name type="ORG">Sanctus</name>, <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name> set out for <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, Land of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> in the first Undead mission of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name>, <name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> of the Catacombs. Long ago, <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> produced its first Undead, a paladin in golden armor. With the legendary treasures <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> and <name type="ORG">Sanctus</name>, <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name> set out for <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, Land of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> in the first Undead mission of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name>, <name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> of the Catacombs. Long ago, <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> produced its first Undead, a paladin in golden armor. With the legendary treasures <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> and <name type="ORG">Sanctus</name>, <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name> set out for <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, Land of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> in the first Undead mission of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name>, <name type="PERSON">Paladin</name> of the Catacombs. Long ago, <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> produced its first Undead, a paladin in golden armor. With the legendary treasures <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> and <name type="ORG">Sanctus</name>, <name type="PERSON">Leeroy</name> set out for <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, Land of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> in the first Undead mission of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dark Mask</name><desc>"Mask of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, former knights of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> who descended into Dark. Some say the skeletal mask of an ancient <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name> is partially fused with the flesh of its face."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dark Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, former knights of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> who descended into Dark. Their armor transformed, and remains a symbol of the Dark servants and their diabolical art of <name type="FAC">Lifedrain</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dark Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, former knights of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> who descended into Dark. Their gauntlets transformed, and remain symbol of the Dark servants and their diabolical art of <name type="FAC">Lifedrain</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dark Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, former knights of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> who descended into Dark. Their leggings transformed, and remain a symbol of the Dark servants and their diabolical art of <name type="FAC">Lifedrain</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brigand Hood</name><desc>"Hood worn by the brigands who raid mountain hamlets and attack travelers. In addition to protecting against the blazing sun, dust, and sand, it helps them tell friend from foe in the heat of battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brigand Armor</name><desc>Armor worn by the brigands who raid mountain hamlets and attack travelers. The addition of metal over a base of cloth and leather offers good mobility and defense.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brigand Gauntlets</name><desc>Gauntlets worn by the brigands who raid mountain hamlets and attack travelers. The addition of metal over a base of cloth and leather offers good mobility and defense.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brigand Trousers</name><desc>Trousers worn by the brigands who raid mountain hamlets and attack travelers. The addition of metal over a base of cloth and leather offers good mobility and defense.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shadow Mask</name><desc>"Black cloth mask worn by spooks from an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Designed so as not to hinder their unique form of martial arts. While it sacrifices defense for the sake of greater mobility, it does offer resistance to bleeding and poison among other things, perhaps due to the nature of their duties."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shadow Garb</name><desc>"Black cloth garb worn by spooks from an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Designed so as not to hinder their unique form of martial arts. While it sacrifices defense for the sake of greater mobility, it does offer resistance to bleeding and poison among other things, perhaps due to the nature of espionage."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shadow Gauntlets</name><desc>"Black cloth gauntlets worn by spooks from an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Designed so as not to hinder their unique form of martial arts. While they sacrifice defense for the sake of greater mobility, they do offer resistance to bleeding and poison among other things, perhaps due to the nature of espionage."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Shadow Leggings</name><desc>"Black cloth leggings worn by spooks from an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Designed so as not to hinder their unique form of martial arts. While they sacrifice defense for the sake of greater mobility, they do offer resistance to bleeding and poison among other things, perhaps due to the nature of espionage."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Iron Helm</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="ORG">Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name></name>, a knight known for his great strength. Built of a special black iron and providing strong defense, notably against fire, but so terribly heavy to be unwieldy to all but <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name> himself."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Iron Armor</name><desc>"Armor of <name type="ORG">Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name></name>, a knight known for his great strength. Built of a special black iron and providing strong defense, notably against fire, but so terribly heavy to be unwieldy to all but <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name> himself."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Iron Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="ORG">Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name></name>, a knight known for his great strength. Built of a special black iron and providing strong defense, notably against fire, but so terribly heavy to be unwieldy to all but <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name> himself."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Iron Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="ORG">Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name></name>, a knight known for his great strength. Built of a special black iron and providing strong defense, notably against fire, but so terribly heavy to be unwieldy to all but <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name> himself."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Smough</name>'s Helm</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="GPE">Smough</name>, the Executioner, protector of the cathedral at the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. It offers extremely high defense and can be worn by humans, but not without great difficulty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Smough</name>'s Armor</name><desc>"Armor of <name type="GPE">Smough</name>, the Executioner, protector of the cathedral at the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. It offers extremely high defense and can be worn by humans, but not without great difficulty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Smough</name>'s Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="GPE">Smough</name>, the Executioner, protector of the cathedral at the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. It offers extremely high defense and can be worn by humans, but not without great difficulty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Smough</name>'s Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="GPE">Smough</name>, the Executioner, protector of the cathedral at the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. It offers extremely high defense and can be worn by humans, but not without great difficulty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Six-Eyed Helm of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name></name><desc>"Helm of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name>, sorcerers that serve <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. The six eyes arranged in two vertical columns compensate for Seath's lack of sight. The heaviest of protective gear for sorcerers, and imbued with magic."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Robe of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name></name><desc>"Robe of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name>, sorcerers that serve <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Even after the onset of Seath's madness, the \snatchers,\""as they were often called, ventured to far lands to find suitable human specimens. The heaviest of protective gear for sorcerers, and imbued with magic."""</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gauntlets of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name></name><desc>"Gauntlets of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name>, sorcerers that serve <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Even after the onset of Seath's madness, the \snatchers,\""as they were often called, ventured to far lands to find suitable human specimens. The heaviest of protective gear for sorcerers, and imbued with magic."""</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> of the <name type="GPE">Channelers</name>, sorcerers that serve <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Even after the onset of Seath's madness, the \snatchers,\""as they were often called, ventured to far lands to find suitable human specimens. The heaviest of protective gear for sorcerers, and imbued with magic."""</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Helm of Favor</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="PERSON">Lautrec</name> the Embraced, representing the goddess <name type="ORG">Fina</name>'s love. During his solitude, he forsook everything, for he believed in the goddess's love for him."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Embraced Armor of Favor</name><desc>"Armor of <name type="PERSON">Lautrec</name> the Embraced, representing the goddess <name type="ORG">Fina</name>'s love. The goddess's arms wrap around it, as if to embrace the wearer."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gauntlets of Favor</name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="PERSON">Lautrec</name> the Embraced, representing the goddess <name type="ORG">Fina</name>'s love. During his solitude, he forsook everything, for he believed in the goddess's love for him."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leggings of Favor</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="PERSON">Lautrec</name> the Embraced, representing the goddess <name type="ORG">Fina</name>'s love. During his solitude, he forsook everything, for he believed in the goddess's love for him."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Helm of the Wise</name><desc>"A strange helm from the ancient land of <name type="ORG">Zena</name>, birthplace of the curious dealer Domhnall. The two horns are believed to symbolize wisdom."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Armor of the Glorious</name><desc>"Strange armor from the ancient land of <name type="ORG">Zena</name>, birthplace of the curious dealer Domhnall. The many medals are believed to symbolize glory."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gauntlets of the Vanquisher</name><desc>"Strange gauntlets from the ancient land of <name type="ORG">Zena</name>, birthplace of the curious dealer Domhnall. The gold bracelets symbolize a vanquisher."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Boots of the Explorer</name><desc>"Strange boots from the ancient land of <name type="ORG">Zena</name>, birthplace of the curious dealer Domhnall. The inlaid silver rings symbolize an explorer."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Helm</name><desc>"Moss-covered helm of the <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>, defender of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>. The <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> is a product of ancient magic, and although this helm is also imbued with magic, it is incredibly heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Armor</name><desc>"Moss-covered armor of the <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>, defender of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>. The <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> is a product of ancient magic, and although this armor is also imbued with magic, it is incredibly heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Moss-covered gauntlets of the <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>, defender of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>. The <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> is a product of ancient magic, and although these gauntlets are also imbued with magic, they are incredibly heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Moss-covered leggings of the <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>, defender of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>. The <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> is a product of ancient magic, and although these leggings are also imbued with magic, they are incredible heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crystalline Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by a <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ed knight, who was partially crystallized. The crystal provides powerful defense, but it cannot be used for long because it is easily broken and cannot be repaired."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crystalline Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by a <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ed knight, who was partially crystallized. The crystal provides powerful defense, but it cannot be used for long because it is easily broken and cannot be repaired."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crystalline Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by a <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ed knight, who was partially crystallized. The crystal provides strong defense, but they cannot be used for long because they are easily broken and cannot be repaired."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crystalline Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings worn by a <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ed knight, who was partially crystallized. The crystal power provides good defense, but they cannot be used for long because they are easily broken and cannot be repaired."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mask of the Sealer</name><desc>"Mask of the sorcerers who flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to seal away the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and the Four Kings who descended into Dark. It symbolizes their resolve to keep the seal shut forever and their atonement for all who were sacrificed, but two of the three forsook <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> upon tiring of their duty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crimson Robe</name><desc>"Robe of the sorcerers who flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to seal away the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and the Four Kings who descended into Dark. The Sealers were once known as healers, and the bright crimson was a symbol of that."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crimson Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves of the sorcerers who flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to seal away the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and the Four Kings who descended into Dark. The Sealers were once known as healers, and the bright crimson was a symbol of that."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crimson <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> of the sorcerers who flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to seal away the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and the Four Kings who descended into Dark. The Sealers were once known as healers, and the bright crimson was a symbol of that."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mask of <name type="ORG">Velka</name></name><desc>"Mask worn by pardoners serving <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. The pardoners listen to the confessions of sinners, urging reflection and salvation. Their masks symbolize separation from worldly desires."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Cleric Robe</name><desc>"Robe worn by pardoners serving <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. The pardoners' attire is uniformly black in color and said to be imbued with <name type="ORG">Velka</name>'s mystical power, which provides resistance against all manner of magic."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Manchette</name><desc>"Manchette worn by pardoners serving <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. The pardoners' attire is uniformly black in color and said to be imbued with <name type="ORG">Velka</name>'s mystical power, which provides resistance against all manner of magic."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Tights</name><desc>"Tights worn by pardoners serving <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. The pardoners' attire is uniformly black in color and said to be imbued with <name type="ORG">Velka</name>'s mystical power, which provides resistance against all manner of magic."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Iron Helm</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. Of high quality, but lacking any particular powers. <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s incredible prowess must have come from rigorous training alone, for his equipment exhibits no special traits."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Armor of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name></name><desc>"Armor of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. The large holy symbol of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>, while powerless, was painted by <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> himself. <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s incredible prowess must have come from rigorous training alone, for his equipment exhibits no special traits."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Iron Bracelet</name><desc>"Bracelets of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. Of high quality, but lacking any particular powers. <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s incredible prowess must have come from rigorous training alone, for his equipment exhibits no special traits."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Iron Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. Of high quality, but lacking any particular powers. <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s incredible prowess must have come from rigorous training alone, for his equipment exhibits no special traits."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chain Helm</name><desc>"A chainmail helm of thin interlinking rings of steel. It is common throughout the human world since it can be easily produced, is not too heavy, and offers good defense. <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s may favor flashy armor, but for warriors on the battlefield, anything is fine as long as it keeps them alive."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chain Armor</name><desc>"Chainmail armor of thin interlinking rings of steel. It is common throughout the human world since it can be easily produced, is not too heavy, and offers good defense. <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s may favor flashy armor, but for warriors on the battlefield, anything is fine as long as it keeps them alive."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leather Gauntlets</name><desc>Gauntlets made of soft leather. One of the more common kinds of protective gear.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chain Leggings</name><desc>"Chainmail leggings of thin interlinking rings of steel. It is common throughout the human world since it can be easily produced, is not too heavy, and offers good defense. <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s may favor flashy armor, but for warriors on the battlefield, anything is fine as long as it keeps them alive."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Cleric Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. It is rather substantial in size and weight, making its wearer look even bigger than he actually is."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Cleric Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. It is rather substantial in size and weight, making its wearer look even bigger than he actually is."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Cleric Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. They are rather substantial in size and weight, making its wearer look even bigger than he actually is."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Cleric Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. They are rather substantial in size and weight, making its wearer look even bigger than he actually is."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Maggot</name><desc>"A loathsome parasite that inhabits Lost <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. It is completely immobile, yet still lives. When worn on the head, it emanates blinding light, which is why it is known as a <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Maggot."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Helm of Thorns</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns and notorious member of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s. A dense patch of thorns grows from its surface. It is a fitting item for the murderous <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, for by simply wearing it and rolling, one can damage enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Armor of Thorns</name><desc>"Armor of <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns and notorious member of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s. A dense patch of thorns grows from its surface. It is a fitting item for the murderous <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, for by simply wearing it and rolling, one can damage enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gauntlets of Thorns</name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns and notorious member of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s. A dense patch of thorns grows from their surface. They are fitting items for the murderous <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, for by simply wearing them and rolling, one can damage enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leggings of Thorns</name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns and notorious member of the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s. A dense patch of thorns grows from their surface. They are fitting items for the murderous <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, for by simply wearing them and rolling, one can damage enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Standard Helm</name><desc>"A sturdy helm made of iron. Very common type of protective gear, it provides a sound level of defense. It is wise to wear a sturdy form of head protection against arrows and other physical threats."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Hard Leather Armor</name><desc>"Armor made of thick leather. Very common type of protective gear, it provides a sound level of defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Hard Leather Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets made of thick leather. Very common type of protective gear, they provide a sound level of defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Hard Leather Boots</name><desc>"Boots made of thick leather. Very common type of protective gear, they provide a sound level of defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sorcerer Hat</name><desc>Hat worn by proper sorcerers who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The majority take pride in having studied at the academy and look down on breaking the formal dress code established for sorcerers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sorcerer <name type="PERSON">Cloak</name></name><desc><name type="PERSON">Cloak</name> worn by proper sorcerers who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The majority take pride in having studied at the academy and look down on breaking the formal dress code established for sorcerers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sorcerer Gauntlets</name><desc>Gauntlets worn by proper sorcerers who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The majority take pride in having studied at the academy and look down on breaking the formal dress code established for sorcerers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sorcerer Boots</name><desc>Boots worn by proper sorcerers who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The majority take pride in having studied at the academy and look down on breaking the formal dress code established for sorcerers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Tattered Cloth Hood</name><desc>"Hood worn by pyromancers of the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Though it appears tattered, it is actually quite strong. Their attire offers substantial protection against poison, fire, and other forces of nature out in the hinterlands where they were driven."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Tattered Cloth Robe</name><desc>"Robe worn by pyromancers of the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Though it appears tattered, it is actually quite strong. Their attire offers substantial protection against poison, fire, and other forces of nature out in the hinterlands where they were driven."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Tattered Cloth Manchette</name><desc>"Manchette worn by pyromancers of the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Though it appears tattered, it is actually quite strong. Their attire offers substantial protection against poison, fire, and other forces of nature out in the hinterlands where they were driven."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Heavy Boots</name><desc>"Boots made of thick leather. The boots of the pyromancers are incredibly tough, on account of the rugged grasslands and treacherous swamps they must traverse. Their soles are nearly impenetrable."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pharis</name>'s Hat</name><desc>"Broad-brimmed hat favored by the archer hero <name type="PERSON">Pharis</name>. <name type="PERSON">Pharis</name> was an accomplished archer, and though he was human, he ranked alongside Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. His hat is universally popular among children."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leather Armor</name><desc>Armor made of soft leather. Very common type of protective gear.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leather Gloves</name><desc>Gloves made of soft leather. Very common type of protective gear.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leather Boots</name><desc>Boots made of soft leather. Very common type of protective gear.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Painting <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Hood</name><desc>"Hood worn by the alabaster-clothed guardians of the paintings in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Offers substantial protection versus magic. They have guarded the Great Paintings of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name> for ages, passing their duty down through the generations, but the reason for doing so passed from all memory long ago."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Painting <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Robe</name><desc>"Robe worn by the alabaster-clothed guardians of the paintings in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Offers substantial protection versus magic. They have guarded the Great Paintings of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name> for ages, passing their duty down through the generations, but the reason for doing so passed from all memory long ago."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Painting <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves worn by the alabaster-clothed guardians of the paintings in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Offer substantial protection versus magic. They have guarded the Great Paintings of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name> for ages, passing their duty down through the generations, but the reason for doing so passed from all memory long ago."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Painting <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> worn by the alabaster-clothed guardians of the paintings in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Offers substantial protection versus magic. They have guarded the Great Paintings of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name> for ages, passing their duty down through the generations, but the reason for doing so passed from all memory long ago."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>'s Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name> is believed to be the captain of the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. His golden lion helm is imbued with the power of lightning and should provide good protection against it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>'s Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name> is believed to be the captain of the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. His golden lion armor is imbued with the power of lightning and should provide good protection against it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>'s Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name> is believed to be the captain of the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. His golden lion gauntlets are imbued with the power of lightning and should provide good protection against it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>'s Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name> is believed to be the captain of the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. His golden lion leggings are imbued with the power of lightning and should provide good protection against it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name>ern Helm</name><desc>"A distinctive helm made in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Exquisitely crafted, this helm offers excellent defense, particularly versus slash attacks, which are one of the main threats in battles in the <name type="LOC">East</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name>ern Armor</name><desc>"Distinctive armor made in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern Land. Exquisitely crafted, this armor offers excellent defense, particularly versus slash attacks, which are one of the main threats in battles in the <name type="LOC">East</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name>ern Gauntlets</name><desc>"Distinctive gauntlets made in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Exquisitely crafted, these gauntlets offer excellent defense, particularly versus slash attacks, which are one of the main threats in battles in the <name type="LOC">East</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name>ern Leggings</name><desc>"Distinctive leggings made in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Exquisitely crafted, these leggings offer excellent defense, particularly versus slash attacks, which are one of the main threats in battles in the <name type="LOC">East</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Xanthous Crown</name><desc>"A mysterious item once worn by <name type="PERSON">the Xanthous King Jeremiah</name>, the legendary exile. No one knows where it came from. The crown bears high-quality cloth which is quite soft to the touch, but its bright yellow color stings the eyes, and it is clearly far too big."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Xanthous Overcoat</name><desc>"A mysterious item once worn by <name type="PERSON">the Xanthous King Jeremiah</name>, the legendary exile. No one knows where it came from. It may be tattered, but its bright yellow color still stings the eyes."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Xanthous Gloves</name><desc>"Mysterious items once worn by <name type="PERSON">the Xanthous King Jeremiah</name>, the legendary exile. No one knows where they came from. They may be tattered, but their bright yellow color still stings the eyes."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Xanthous <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc>"A mysterious item once worn by <name type="PERSON">the Xanthous King Jeremiah</name>, the legendary exile. No one knows where it came from. It may be tattered, but its bright yellow color still stings the eyes."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Thief Mask</name><desc>"Mask of sinners. They hide their faces, stifle their voices and hide in the shadows. It does not provide much in the way of defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Leather Armor</name><desc>"This armor made of smooth black leather is extremely quiet, a good thing for those who hide in the shadows. The leather itself is thick, offering a decent level of protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Leather Gloves</name><desc>"These gloves made of smooth black leather are extremely quiet, good for those who hide in the shadows. The leather itself is thick, offering a decent level of protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Leather Boots</name><desc>"These boots made of smooth black leather are extremely quiet, good for those who hide in the shadows. The leather itself is thick, offering a decent level of protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Priest's Hat</name><desc>Distinctive hat worn only by Way of White priests in <name type="PERSON">Thorolund</name>. It is simply meant to show their position within the hierarchy. It holds almost no meaning in the land of <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Holy Robe</name><desc>"Robe donned by men of the cloth. Though plain to the eye, its hardy fabric repels rain and keeps the body warm. Those dissatisfied with church teachings must test their faith by going on a spiritual journey. Such is the ritual self-purification of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Traveling Gloves</name><desc>"Thick, sturdy gloves made for travelers on extended journeys."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Holy Trousers</name><desc>"Trousers donned by men of the cloth. Though plain to the eye, their hardy fabric repels rain and keeps the body warm. Those dissatisfied with church teachings must test their faith by going on a spiritual journey. Such is the ritual self-purification of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who haunt <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. The knights followed Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> when he departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> but they were burned to ashes in the newly kindled flame, wandering the world as disembodied spirits ever after."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who haunt <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. The knights followed Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> when he departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, but they were burned to ashes in the newly kindled flame, wandering the world as disembodied spirits ever after."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who haunt <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. The knights pursued Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> when he departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, but they were burned to ashes in the newly kindled flame, wandering the world as disembodied spirits ever after."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who haunt <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. The knights followed Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> when he departed to link the flame, but they were burned to ashes in the newly kindled fire, wandering the world as disembodied spirits ever after."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crown of Dusk</name><desc>"Special magic crown bestowed upon Dusk, Princess of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>, upon her birth. Its wearer is blessed by all manner of magic. This raises the power and effect of the wearer's magic, but damage suffered by magic attacks also rises."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Antiquated Dress</name><desc>"A dress from the ancient fallen land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Its ivory-colored silk features elaborate embroidery and is imbued with ancient magic power. One cannot expect any physical protection from this garment, as it was not meant to be worn in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Antiquated Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves from the ancient fallen land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Their ivory-colored silk features elaborate embroidery and are imbued with ancient magic power. One cannot expect any physical protection from these, as they were not meant to be worn in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Antiquated Skirt</name><desc>"A skirt from the ancient fallen land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Its ivory-colored silk features elaborate embroidery and is imbued with ancient magic power. One cannot expect any physical protection from this garment, as it was not meant to be worn in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Witch Hat</name><desc>"Hat of the rogue witch <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>. Almost all magic users that employ a wand studied at <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, but <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name> is one of the few exceptions. She braved the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> but did not live to tell of her ordeal."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Witch <name type="PERSON">Cloak</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Cloak</name> of the rogue witch <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>. Almost all magic users that employ catalysts studied at <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, but <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name> is one of the few exceptions. She braved the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> but did not live to tell of her ordeal."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Witch Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves of the rogue witch <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>. Almost all magic users that employ catalysts studied at <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, but <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name> is one of the few exceptions. She braved the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> but did not live to tell of her ordeal."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Witch Skirt</name><desc>"Skirt of the rogue witch <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>. Almost all magic users that employ catalysts studied at <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, but <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name> is one of the few exceptions. She braved the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> but did not live to tell of her ordeal."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of a nameless knight, perhaps an elite knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Although he was loath to give up on his Undead mission, he perished at <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name>, and went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of a nameless knight, perhaps an elite knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, based on the fire-warding heraldic symbol on its blue surcoat. Although he was loath to give up on his Undead mission, he perished at <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name>, and went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of a nameless knight, perhaps an elite knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Although he was loath to give up on his Undead mission, he perished at <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name>, and went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of a nameless knight, perhaps an elite knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Although he was loath to give up on his Undead mission, he perished at <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name>, and went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wanderer Hood</name><desc>"Hood of an aimless traveler. Made from sturdy leather, it offers protection versus wind and rain."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wanderer Coat</name><desc>"Coat of an aimless traveler. Made from sturdy leather and quilting. Battle comes with the territory when one wanders the land, and this coat provides a certain degree of protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wanderer Manchette</name><desc>Manchette of an aimless traveler. Made from sturdy leather and protects the hands.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Wanderer Boots</name><desc>Boots of an aimless traveler. Made from sturdy leather. A must-have for long journeys.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mage Smith Hat</name><desc>"Hat worn by proper mage smiths who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Mage smiths learn their craft alongside sorcerers, but apply their sorcery to forging weapons with magic embers."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mage Smith Coat</name><desc>"Coat worn by proper mage smiths who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Mage smiths learn their craft alongside sorcerers, but apply their sorcery to forging weapons with magic embers."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mage Smith Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by proper mage smiths who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Mage smiths learn their craft alongside sorcerers, but apply their sorcery to forging weapons with magic embers."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mage Smith Boots</name><desc>"Boots worn by proper mage smiths who studied at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Mage smiths learn their craft alongside sorcerers, but apply their sorcery to forging weapons with magic embers."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Big Hat</name></name><desc>"Gigantic hat worn by the great sorcerer <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. It completely hid his face, which led to his nickname \<name type="ORG">Big Hat</name>.\"" Famously antisocial, <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> used it to block out noise and people's stares so he could focus on his own thoughts, but it does not possess any special magic powers."""</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sage Robe</name><desc>"Robe worn by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. It is said to have been from his apprentice days at <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, but it is so worn out, no one knows what it originally looked like. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>, who cared little for his appearance, no doubt ever bothered to change out of it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Traveling Gloves</name><desc>Gloves worn by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. They are indistinguishable from the ordinary kind worn by travelers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Traveling Boots</name><desc>Boots worn by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. They are indistinguishable from the ordinary kind worn by travelers.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of a lower-rank knight. Despite the thin metal used, the grooved texture gives it added protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of a lower-rank knight. Despite the thin metal used, the grooved texture gives it added protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of a lower-rank knight. Despite the thin metal used, the grooved texture gives them added protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of a lower-rank knight. Despite the thin metal used, the grooved texture gives them added protection."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dingy Hood</name><desc>"Worn by the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> at <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. It is thought to have once been the white hood of a maiden, but smoke and ashes from bonfires have darkened it over the years."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dingy Robe</name><desc>"Worn by the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> at <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. It is thought to have once been the white robe of a maiden, but smoke and ashes from bonfires have darkened it over the years."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dingy Gloves</name><desc>"Worn by the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> at <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. They are thought to have once been the white gloves of a maiden, but smoke and ashes from bonfires have darkened them over the years."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Blood-Stained Skirt</name><desc>"Worn by the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> at <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. It is thought to have once been the white skirt of a maiden, but its true origin is lost in patches of blood. Perhaps its former wearer was maimed to prevent escape?"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Maiden Hood</name><desc>"White hood worn by traveling maidens. It is part of their formal attire, regardless of rank. It is soft and well-made, but does not offer much in the way of defense, making it ill- suited to use in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Maiden Robe</name><desc>"White robe worn by traveling maidens. It is part of their formal attire, regardless of rank. It is soft and well-made, but does not offer much in the way of defense, making it ill- suited to use in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Maiden Gloves</name><desc>"White gloves worn by traveling maidens. They are part of their formal attire, regardless of rank. While soft and well-made, they do not offer much in the way of defense, making them ill-suited to use in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Maiden Skirt</name><desc>"White skirt worn by traveling maidens. It is part of their formal attire, regardless of rank. It is soft and well-made, but does not offer much in the way of defense, making it ill- suited to use in battle."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who protect <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. When Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, his knights split into two groups. The Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s remained in the forsaken capital in the service of their goddess."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who protect <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. When Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, his knights split into two groups. The Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s remained in the forsaken capital in the service of their goddess."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who protect <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. When Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, his knights split into two groups. The Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s remained in the forsaken capital in the service of their goddess."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s who protect <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. When Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> departed to link the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, his knights split into two groups. The Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s remained in the forsaken capital in the service of their goddess."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock's warriors. Carved from solid rock, its tremendous weight is matched only by the defense it provides. <name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s warriors never flinched nor retreated from battle. Those unfortunate enough to face them were inevitably beaten to a pulp."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock's warriors. Carved from solid rock, its tremendous weight is matched only by the defense it provides. <name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s warriors never flinched nor retreated from battle. Those unfortunate enough to face them were inevitably beaten to a pulp."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock's warriors. Carved from solid rock, their tremendous weight is matched only by the defense they provide. <name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s warriors never flinched nor retreated from battle. Those unfortunate enough to face them were inevitably beaten to a pulp."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings worn by <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock's warriors. Carved from solid rock, their tremendous weight is matched only by the defense they provide. <name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s warriors never flinched nor retreated from battle. Those unfortunate enough to face them were inevitably beaten to a pulp."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brass Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>ess, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. After becoming Undead, she visited the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin at the Mausoleum of the Spiral Depths, became a Blade of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>, and assumed the flame-keeping duty. She received this helm, which hides her hideous form and helps her hunt the guilty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brass Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>ess, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. After becoming Undead, she visited the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin at the Mausoleum of the Spiral Depths, became a Blade of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>, and assumed the flame-keeping duty. She received this armor, which hides her hideous form and helps her hunt the guilty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brass Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>ess, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. After becoming Undead, she visited the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin at the Mausoleum of the Spiral Depths, became a Blade of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>, and assumed the flame-keeping duty. She received these gauntlets, which hide her hideous form and help her hunt the guilty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Brass Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>ess, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. After becoming Undead, she visited the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin at the Mausoleum of the Spiral Depths, became a Blade of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>, and assumed the flame-keeping duty. She received these leggings, which hide her hideous form and help her hunt the guilty."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gold-Hemmed Black Hood</name><desc>"Worn by the witch <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, mother of pyromancy and <name type="ORG">Daughter of Chaos</name>. She wore this gold-hemmed black hood before even the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, and it offers strong resistance versus fire, poison, and other perils."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gold-Hemmed Black <name type="PERSON">Cloak</name></name><desc>"Worn by the witch <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, mother of pyromancy and <name type="ORG">Daughter of Chaos</name>. She wore this gold-hemmed black cloak before even the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, and it offers strong resistance versus fire, poison, and other perils."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gold-Hemmed Black Gloves</name><desc>"Worn by the witch <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, mother of pyromancy and <name type="ORG">Daughter of Chaos</name>. She wore these gold-lined black gloves before even the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, and they offer strong resistance versus fire, poison, and other perils."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gold-Hemmed Black Skirt</name><desc>"Worn by the witch <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, founder of pyromancy and one of <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name>. She wore this gold-hemmed black skirt before even the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, and it offers strong resistance versus fire, poison, and other perils."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Golem Helm</name><desc>"Head of the Iron Golem, guardian of the ancient Sen's Fortress, slayer of heroes who ventured forth to <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Without its core, it is a mere hunk of iron, and can be equipped as solid protective gear, but its immense weight hinders stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Golem Armor</name><desc>"Body of the Iron Golem, guardian of the ancient Sen's Fortress, slayer of heroes who ventured forth to <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Without its core, it is a mere hunk of iron, and can be equipped as solid protective gear, but its immense weight hinders stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Golem Gauntlets</name><desc>"Arms of the Iron Golem, guardian of the ancient Sen's Fortress, slayer of heroes who ventured forth to <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Without its core, they are mere hunks of iron, and can be equipped as solid protective gear, but their immense weight hinders stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Golem Leggings</name><desc>"Legs of the Iron Golem, guardian of the ancient Sen's Fortress, slayer of heroes who ventured forth to <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Without its core, they are mere hunks of iron, and can be equipped as solid protective gear, but their immense weight hinders stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Soldier Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> soldiers. It may be old and battered, but its iron construction makes it quite sturdy. It is wise to wear a sturdy form of head protection against arrows and other physical threats."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Soldier Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> soldiers. It may be old and battered, but its iron construction makes it quite sturdy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Soldier's Gloves</name><desc>Soldier's Gloves</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Soldier <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc><name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> soldiers. It is so tattered that it barely serves its purpose anymore.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Steel Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, known for their heavy armaments and armor. Countless <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, once extolled as the mightiest of mighty, became Undead and ventured to <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. But their journey was for naught, as they went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, and became a threat to all Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Steel Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, known for their heavy armaments and armor. Countless <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, once extolled as the mightiest of mighty, became Undead and ventured to <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. But their journey was for naught, as they went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, and became a threat to all Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Steel Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, known for their heavy armaments and armor. Countless <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, once extolled as the mightiest of mighty, became Undead and ventured to <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. But their journey was for naught, as they went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, and became a threat to all Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Steel Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, known for their heavy armaments and armor. Countless <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of Berenike, once extolled as the mightiest of mighty, became Undead and ventured to <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. But their journey was for naught, as they went <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, and became a threat to all Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Thief's Hood</name><desc>Hood worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> thieves. Used to hide a guilty countenance.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Thief's Leather Armor</name><desc>Leather armor worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> thieves. It stifles noise and helps its wearer hide in the shadows.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Thief's Gloves</name><desc>Thief's Gloves</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Thief's Tights</name><desc>Tights worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> thieves. They stifle noise and help their wearer hide in the shadows.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by the knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name>. It is made from thick iron plates. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the homeland of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but it came to ruin after a great many Undead were spawned."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by the knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name>. It is made from thick iron plates. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the homeland of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but it came to ruin after a great many Undead were spawned."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by the knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name>. They are made from thick iron plates. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the homeland of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but it came to ruin after a great many Undead were spawned."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings worn by the knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name>. They are made from thick iron plates. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the homeland of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but it came to ruin after a great many Undead were spawned."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> warriors. Although it is made of iron, it is old, battered and worn out. It is wise to wear a sturdy form of head protection against arrows and other physical threats."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> Armor</name><desc>Armor worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> warriors. It is made of thick leather that is tattered with age.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Warrior</name>'s Gloves</name><desc><name type="ORG">Warrior</name>'s Gloves</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc><name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> worn by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> warriors. It is so tattered that it barely serves its purpose anymore.</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Giant Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Made from ancient brass, it also offers protection versus non-physical attacks, but due to its giant size, it is extremely heavy for humans, and impedes stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Giant Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Made from ancient brass, it also offers protection versus non-physical attacks, but due to its giant size, it is extremely heavy for humans, and impedes stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Giant Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Made from ancient brass, they also offer protection versus non-physical attacks, but due to their giant size, they are extremely heavy for humans, and impede stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Giant Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Made from ancient brass, they also offer protection versus non-physical attacks, but due to their giant size, they are extremely heavy for humans, and impede stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crown of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name></name><desc>"Crown of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, protector of the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. This crown of the gods demands faith immeasurable of its wearer, but it is imbued with <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> power that enhances all magic. The image of the sun manifests <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin's deep adoration of the sun."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Robe</name><desc>"Robe of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, protector of the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. The power of the moon was strong in <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, and thus he was raised as a daughter. His magic garb is silk-thin, and hardly provides any physical defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, protector of the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. The power of the moon was strong in <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, and thus he was raised as a daughter. His magic garb is silk-thin, and hardly provides any physical defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, protector of the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. The power of the moon was strong in <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, and thus he was raised as a daughter. His magic garb is silk-thin, and hardly provides any physical defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Crown of the Great Lord</name><desc>"Crown of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder, who linked the First Flame. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, bearer of the ultimate soul, divided his power among his great clan before linking the flame. But he did keep his crown, perhaps to preserve a symbol of the monarch, for its actual power had fully subsided."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Robe of the Great Lord</name><desc>"Robe of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder, who linked the First Flame. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, bearer of the ultimate soul, divided that power among his clan before linking the flame. When he departed, he left only with his greatsword, his garb, and the crown, now bereft of power."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Bracelet of the Great Lord</name><desc>"Bracelets of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder, who linked the First Flame. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, bearer of the ultimate soul, divided that power among his clan before linking the flame. When he departed, he left only with his greatsword, his garb, and the crown, now bereft of power."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Anklet of the Great Lord</name><desc>"Anklets of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder, who linked the First Flame. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, bearer of the ultimate soul, divided that power among his clan before linking the flame. When he departed, he left only with his greatsword, his garb, and the crown, now bereft of power."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Sack</name><desc>"Bloodstained patchwork sack by the Undead man-eating cook lurking in the Depths. Two eyeholes have been haphazardly cut out. It is unexpectedly soft and comfortable to wear, but it is probably near meaningless in terms of defense."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Symbol of Avarice</name><desc>"Monster head resembling a treasure chest. Once an ancient god, it is said this is the symbol of shame imposed on a long lost clan, exiled for the sin of avarice. Wearing this slightly raises soul absorption and item discovery, but also affects its wearer with the curse of the branded."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Royal Helm</name><desc>"Helm of <name type="ORG">Vamos</name>, skeleton blacksmith of the Catacombs. Partially made of gold, and confers high resistance overall. The helm is believed to belong to an ancient royal line, but only <name type="ORG">Vamos</name> would know for sure, and he shall never speak again."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mask of the Father</name><desc>"One of the three masks of the <name type="ORG">Pinwheel</name>, the necromancer who stole the power of the <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name>, and reigns over the Catacombs. This mask, belonging to the valiant father, slightly raises equipment load."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mask of the Mother</name><desc>"One of the three masks of the <name type="ORG">Pinwheel</name>, the necromancer who stole the power of the <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name>, and reigns over the Catacombs. This mask, belonging to the kindly mother, slightly raises <name type="ORG">HP</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Mask of the Child</name><desc>"One of the three masks of the <name type="ORG">Pinwheel</name>, the necromancer who stole the power of the <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name>, and reigns over the Catacombs. This mask, belonging to the naive child, slightly raises stamina recovery speed."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Fang Boar</name> Helm</name><desc>"Severed head of the fully-armored <name type="PERSON">Fang Boar</name> taken by the one who killed it as proof of his victory, just as the Gods once did with the head of the ancient dragon. Can be worn on the head as a surprisingly sound piece of protective gear."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gargoyle Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the gargoyle, an enchanted creature that guarded the Bell of Awakening in the belfry of <name type="ORG">the Undead Church</name>. This bronze helm was for mere appearance's sake, as gargoyle skin is naturally hard. Little in the way of defense can be expected from it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Sorcerer Hat</name><desc>"Hat worn by the secret sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. They secretly work with sound-based spells, and never reveal themselves."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Sorcerer <name type="PERSON">Cloak</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Cloak</name> worn by the secret sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. They secretly work with sound-based spells, and never reveal themselves."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Sorcerer Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by the secret sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. They secretly work with sound-based spells, and never reveal themselves."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Black Sorcerer Boots</name><desc>"Boots worn by the secret sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. They secretly work with sound-based spells, and never reveal themselves."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite Cleric Helm</name><desc>"Helm worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. Among such helms, those that were black belonged to warrior clerics sent on missions, many of whom were high-level priests."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite Cleric Armor</name><desc>"Armor worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. Among such armors, those that were black belonged to warrior clerics sent on missions, many of whom were high-level priests."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite Cleric Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. Among such gauntlets, those that were black belonged to warrior clerics sent on missions, many of whom were high-level priests."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Elite Cleric Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings worn by the warrior clerics of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, who are famous for being unyielding in battle. Among such leggings, those that were black belonged to warrior clerics sent on missions, many of whom were high-level priests."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Helm of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Helm of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The death of the helm's owner can be surmised from the corrosive Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, and the musty azure-blue tassel, once a symbol of pride and glory.     "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Armor of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Armor of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The death of the armor's owner can be surmised from the corrosive Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, and the tattered azure-blue cape, once a symbol of pride and glory.  "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Gauntlets of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Gauntlets of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The death of their owner can be surmised from the corrosive Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, which has compromised their protective utility."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Leggings of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Leggings of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The death of their owner can be surmised from the corrosive Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, which has compromised their protective utility."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Porcelain Mask</name><desc>"Mask of the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The cyclops headpiece is common to all of the Lord's Blades, but <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name> was determined to earn this soft porcelain mask as a unique decoration of honor. The mask is lined with ivory locks of hair."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Lord's Blade Robe</name><desc>"Robe of the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. A robe common to all of the Lord's Blades. These deadly women shift nimbly between layers of darkness, etching streaks of gold into the night air, and planting visions of terror into the minds of their targets."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Lord's Blade Gloves</name><desc>"Gloves worn by the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. Gloves common to all of the Lord's Blades. These deadly women shift nimbly between layers of darkness, etching streaks of gold into the night air, and planting visions of terror into the minds of their targets."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Lord's Blade <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> worn by the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. <name type="PERSON">Waistcloth</name> common to all the Lord's Blades. These deadly women shift nimbly between layers of darkness, etching streaks of gold into the night air, and planting visions of terror into the minds of their targets."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s Helm</name><desc>"Helm of Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. Received as a decoration of knightly honor. A helm crafted especially for the honorable Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, only the eye holes were packed with tree resin by those who dismissed <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> as a brutish giant. "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s Armor</name><desc>"Armor of Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. Armor donned by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> since his days as a dragonslayer. The medallion, bequeathed by the Lord Himself, and the dragon bone pauldrons are symbols of the highest honors."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. Received as a decoration of honor. Crafted of similar material to the gauntlets worn by the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. Received as a decoration of honor. Crafted of similar material to the gauntlets worn by the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Helm</name><desc>"Helm of the stone knights, guardians of the forest sanctuary. The stone knights are golems animated by magic, and their enchanted helms are oppressively heavy. "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Armor</name><desc>"Armor of the stone knights, guardians of the forest sanctuary. The stone knights are golems animated by magic, and their enchanted armor is oppressively heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Gauntlets</name><desc>"Gauntlets of the stone knights, guardians of the forest sanctuary. The stone knights are golems animated by magic, and their enchanted gauntlets are oppressively heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Leggings</name><desc>"Leggings of the stone knights, guardians of the forest sanctuary. The stone knights are golems animated by magic, and their enchanted leggings are oppressively heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Snickering Top Hat</name><desc>"Black top hat worn by <name type="PERSON">Marvellous Chester</name>, a man of mystery lost in the past. The wearer of this top hat cracks a dubious, permanent grin. The Curse of Chester!"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chester's Long Coat</name><desc>"Black leather long coat hat worn by <name type="PERSON">Marvellous Chester</name>, a man of mystery lost in the past. This exquisitely sewn aristocratic suit allows its wearer to move in silence, lending well to stealth."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chester's Gloves</name><desc>"Leather gloves worn by <name type="PERSON">Marvellous Chester</name>, a man of mystery lost in the past. These gloves have no distinguishing features, but are of extremely high quality.  "</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Chester's Trousers</name><desc>"Black leather trousers worn by <name type="PERSON">Marvellous Chester</name>, a man of mystery lost in the past. These exquisitely sewn trousers are decorated with silver trinkets of varying sizes, and have straps on the inner legs for carrying crossbow bolts."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Bloated Head</name><desc>"The head of an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> resident whose humanity went wild after being devoured by the Dark of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. The bloated head is fissured, the cracks lined with innumerable tiny red eyeballs. With a hard outside and mucous-filled inside, no sane person could ever wear it."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Bloated Sorcerer Head</name><desc>"The head of an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> resident whose humanity went wild after being devoured by the Dark of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. The bloated head is fissured, the cracks lined with innumerable tiny red eyeballs, and accented by protruding brain parts. It is lightly enchanted, suggesting that it may have belonged to a sorcerer."</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Head</name><desc>Head</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Body</name><desc>Body</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Arms</name><desc>Arms</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Legs</name><desc>Legs</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>No Travel Gear / Head</name><desc>No Travel Gear / Head</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>No Travel Gear / Body</name><desc>No Travel Gear / Body</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>No Travel Gear / Arms</name><desc>No Travel Gear / Arms</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>No Travel Gear / Legs</name><desc>No Travel Gear / Legs</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dragon Head</name><desc>"Transform the head into that of a dragon with a secret rite of the transcendent apostles. Use Dragon Head <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> in this state to spew dragon breath. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by transformation into an ancient drag"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dragon Body</name><desc>"Transform the body into that of a dragon with a secret rite of the transcendent apostles. Use <name type="PERSON">Dragon Torso <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name> in this state to let out a great dragon roar. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by transformation into an an"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dragon Arms</name><desc>"Transform arms into those of a dragon with a secret rite of the transcendent apostles. Use <name type="PERSON">Dragon Torso <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name> in this state to create dragon roar and wield talons from the hands. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by trans"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Dragon Legs</name><desc>"Transform legs into those of a dragon with a secret rite of the transcendent apostles. Use <name type="PERSON">Dragon Torso <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name> in this state to let out a great dragon roar. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by transformation into an ancie"</desc>
<itemType>Armour</itemType><name>Egg</name><desc>"An egg implanted on the head by a type of parasite bearing eggs on its back. The nightmare begins with a slight itch on the head, and soon the parasite will be siphoning the souls of slain enemies. Unless you find this amusing, quickly use <name type="ORG">Egg Vermifuge</name> to purge it."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>White Sign Soapstone</name><desc>"Online play item. Leave summon sign. Be summoned to another world as a phantom through your sign, and defeat the area boss to acquire humanity. In <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the flow of time is distorted, and <name type="ORG">the White Sign Soapstone</name> allows Undead to assist one another."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Red Sign Soapstone</name><desc>"Online play item. Leave invasion sign. Be summoned to another world as a dark spirit, and defeat the summoner to acquire humanity. Certain <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s resist their descent into dark and persevere along the honorable path. <name type="ORG">The Red Sign Soapstone</name> is for them."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Red Eye Orb</name><desc>Online play item. Invade another world. Defeat the master of the world you have invaded to acquire humanity. The <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Kaathe</name> use this orb to seek humanity and plunge further into dark. Perhaps they are more human than we?</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Black Separation Crystal</name><desc>"This black crystal, long a symbol of farewell, is granted to banished Undead. The crystal sends phantoms back to their homes, or sends you back to yours. Beware of fickle use of this item if you intend to nurture relations."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Orange Guidance Soapstone</name><desc>"Online play item. Write/view/rate message. Messages transmit to other worlds, where they are rated. Also, rate messages of others. In <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the flow of time is distorted, and messages allow Undead to assist (or deceive) one another."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Book of the Guilty</name><desc>"Online play item. Check list of indicted players. The Goddess of Sin <name type="ORG">Velka</name> oversees this list of the guilty, who have disrespected the Gods or their covenants, and shall one day face the wrath of the <name type="ORG">Blades of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name></name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Eye of Death</name><desc>"Online play item. Lure phantoms from other worlds. The dreadful Eyes of Death spread disaster across neighboring worlds. Phantoms lured to the host world may end up as victims, allowing the Eyes of Death to multiply, and leading to further proliferation of bane."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Cracked Red Eye Orb</name><desc>Online play item. Invade another world. Defeat the master of the world you have invaded to acquire humanity. The Cracked Red Eye Orb allows players to temporarily imitate this ability normally limited to the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s of <name type="PERSON">Kaathe</name>.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Servant Roster</name><desc>"Online play item. Check servants of <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name>. Egg-bearer <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> keeps this roster of those who serve his master, a <name type="ORG">Daughter of Chaos</name>. <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> praises those who offer significant humanity to alleviate his master's suffering. But what is praise from <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> really worth?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Blue Eye Orb</name><desc>"Online play item. Invade world of player in Book of the Guilty. Subdue player to acquire Souvenir of <name type="ORG">Reprisal</name>. These mystical orbs are granted to <name type="ORG">Blades of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name></name>, knights who serve the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, so that they may serve the Gods in meting out vengeance."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dragon Eye</name><desc>"Online play item. Find a player who has acquired a Dragon Scale and invade that player's world to pillage it. An art of the transcendent apostles who pray to the ancient dragons. To be alive is to be vulnerable, and the fiery Gods are no exception. The apostles seek another plane of existence, which transcends life.     "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Black Eye Orb</name><desc>"Mystical orb found on a <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>'s corpse Invade the world of the murderer of a <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>, to defeat the perpetrator and reclaim the soul of the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>. <name type="ORG">The Black Eye</name> keeps constant watch on the city of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Black Eye Orb</name><desc>"Invade the world of the traitor <name type="PERSON">Shiva</name>. Invade the world of <name type="PERSON">Shiva</name>, and subdue him to reclaim the Blade of Chaos. But <name type="ORG">the Black Eye</name> has lost its focus, and its powers waver timorously. Where could the traitor <name type="PERSON">Shiva</name> be? "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Darksign</name><desc>"The Darksign signifies an accursed Undead. Those branded with it are reborn after death, but will one day lose their mind and go <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Death triggers the Darksign, which returns its bearer to the last bonfire rested at, but at the cost of all humanity and souls."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Purple Coward's Crystal</name><desc>"Online play item. Quit Battle of Stoicism. (Session ends if host leaves) Victory in this battle once led to ancient <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>, but even in the absence of its overseer, capitulation is a disgrace. In the name of a warrior's honor, do not quickly resort to use of this crystal."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Estus</name> Flask</name><desc>"The Undead treasure these dull green flasks. Fill with <name type="ORG">Estus</name> at bonfire. Fills <name type="ORG">HP</name>. The <name type="ORG">Estus</name> Flasks are linked to the <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>s. The Dark Tales also make reference:  An emerald flask, from the <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>'s soul She lives to protect the flame, And dies to protect it further "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Silver Pendant</name><desc>"Silver pendant engraved with the crest of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>. One of the ancient treasures of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Presented to <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> for facing the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. Effectively deflects the Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, especially in its magic forms."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Elizabeth</name>'s Mushroom</name><desc>"Large medicinal mushroom of <name type="PERSON">Elizabeth</name>, keeper of the sanctuary. Eating this mushroom invigorates the flesh, and greatly restores <name type="ORG">HP</name> for a limited duration. Its dramatic effect can make the difference between a warrior's life and death."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Divine Blessing</name><desc>"Holy water from Goddess <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere. Fully restore <name type="ORG">HP</name> and undo irregularities. The Goddess of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, daughter of the great Lord of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, is cherished by all as the symbol of bounty and fertility.   "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Green Blossom</name><desc>"Green weed, shaped like a flower. Temporary boost to stamina recovery speed. This uniquely bitter, biting herb is sometimes harvested in large quantities, but normally it is an annual plant found near water."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Bloodred Moss Clump</name><desc>"Medicinal red moss clump. Reduces bleeding build-up. Bleeding builds up when attacked by sharp blades or spikes, and once triggered causes severe damage. Use this moss clump before it reaches this point."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Purple Moss Clump</name><desc>"Medicinal purple moss clump. Reduces poison build-up. Cures poison. Poison builds up in the body, and when it breaks out, it causes gradual damage over a period of time. Poison can be exasperating, so be certain to carry the needed quantity of these moss clumps when destined for an afflicted area."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Blooming Purple Moss Clump</name><desc>"Potently medicinal moss clump with a flower. Reduces poison and toxin. Restores status. Toxin is a more vicious form of poison which quickly leads to death. Moss clumps without a flower are useless against toxin, and a lack of these moss clumps could lead to an early demise."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Purging <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name><desc>"Ash-colored stone encasing a skull. Secret treasure of <name type="PERSON">Arstor</name>, the Earl of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>. Reduces curse build-up and breaks curse. Humans are helpless against curses, and can only redirect their influence. The Purging <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> does not dispel curses, but receives them as a surrogate. The stone itself was once a person or some other being."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Egg Vermifuge</name></name><desc>"Bitter, sour chestnut. Removes parasitic egg from body. The egg-bearers have chosen to serve the Flame of Chaos, and the eggs symbolize this selfless choice. Naturally, these chestnuts are forbidden, but are allowed under special circumstances."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Repair Powder</name></name><desc>"Lightly enchanted golden powder. Repairs weapon equipped in right hand. Use of a weapon depletes its durability, eventually rendering it ineffective. <name type="ORG">Repair Powder</name> is a precious method of repair on the battlefield, as it obviates the need for a Repairbox.     "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Throwing Knife</name><desc>"Throwing knife. Used as a projectile. Throwing knives have limited range and accuracy compared to arrows, but offer a quick-and-easy ranged attack. Undead who lack other means of ranged attacks will do well to stock a few of these."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Poison Throwing Knife</name><desc>"Throwing knife. Coated with poison. Throwing knives have limited range and accuracy compared to arrows, but offer a quick-and-easy ranged attack. When a foe is poisoned, it will continually take damage over a period of time. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name>bomb</name><desc>"Bisque urn filled with black powder. Explodes, inflicting fire damage. Relatively powerful ranged weapon, especially in situations calling for fire damage. A very precious item at low levels. Many warriors use these to augment their strategic repertoire."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dung Pie</name><desc>"Atrocious fecal waste material. Throw at enemy to build up toxins, but also builds up your toxicity. Although the stench makes it difficult to carry on one's person, turning an enemy toxic inflicts high damage over a period of time."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Alluring Skull</name><desc>"A skull with meekly lingering souls. Throw to shatter and spread souls to attract certain types of enemies. Souls are a concentration of life, and the life-starved <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>s are lured by its power. Not effective for all enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Lloyd</name>'s Talisman</name><desc>"Talisman utilized by <name type="PERSON">Allfather <name type="PERSON">Lloyd</name></name>'s cleric knights to hunt down the Undead. Blocks <name type="ORG">Estus</name> recovery within a limited area. In the outside world, the Undead are accursed creatures, and <name type="PERSON">Lloyd</name>'s cleric knights are widely praised for their Undead hunts. This blessed talisman blocks Undead recovery, allowing the knights to fight with impunity.  "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Black <name type="ORG">Fire</name>bomb</name><desc>"Black bisque urn filled with black powder. Explodes, inflicting fire damage. Powerful ranged weapon, especially in situations calling for fire damage. A very precious item at low levels. Black <name type="ORG">Fire</name>bombs are especially destructive."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Charcoal Pine Resin</name><desc>"Black charcoal-like pine resin. Applies fire to right-hand weapon. Affected weapon inflicts fire damage for a short time. Particularly effective against corporeal creatures and Undead, who have an instinctual fear of fire."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Gold Pine Resin</name><desc>"Rare pine resin which emits golden sparks. Applies lightning to right-hand weapon. Affected weapon inflicts rare lightning damage, making it effective against targets which are resilient to both magic and fire. Very effective against dragon family foes."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Transient Curse</name><desc>"Limb of the victim of a curse. Temporary curse allows engagement with ghosts. The only way to fight back against ghosts, who are cursed beings, is to become cursed oneself. The safest method, however dreadful, is to cut off an arm of the dead."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Rotten Pine Resin</name><desc>"Rotten pine resin that has gained poison. Adds poison effect to right-hand weapon. Hits with affected weapon build up enemy poison level. If enemy is poisoned, damage will be inflicted for a period of time."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Homeward Bone</name><desc>"Bone fragment reduced to white ash. Return to last bonfire used for resting. Bonfires are fueled by bones of the Undead. In rare cases, the strong urge of their previous owner's to seek bonfires enchants their bones with a homeward instinct."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Humanity</name><desc>"Rare tiny black sprite found on corpses Use to gain 1 humanity This black sprite is called humanity, but little is known about its true nature. If the soul is the source of all life, then what distinction is left for humanity?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Prism <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name><desc>"Warm pebble emitting a beautiful phasing aura of seven colors, with a very rare eighth. The rainbow stone does nothing special, but can serve as a path marker, and can be dropped off a cliff to judge height by the sound of its descent. If a loud noise is heard upon its landing, then a fall off the ledge is surely lethal.   "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Binoculars</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Binoculars</name> made of brass. Use to peer at distant scenery. This advanced device was built by a famous craftsman of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Its utility is singular, but its applications many. The value of these specs depends greatly on the imagination of their owner."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Affidavit</name><desc>"Slip sold by bishop of <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, Goddess of <name type="PERSON">Sin Annul</name> a covenant without committing sin A covenant is a most sacred union, normally not subject to negotiation, but when circumstances require it, even <name type="ORG">Goddess <name type="ORG">Velka</name></name> will make an exception. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Indictment</name><desc>"Slip sold by bishop of <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, Goddess of Sin. If you are killed by an invader, use this to report the crime of that trespasser. The indicted player will be added to a list of unfortunate souls who will one day face the wrath of the <name type="ORG">Blades of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name></name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Souvenir of <name type="ORG">Reprisal</name></name><desc>"Blood-drained, shrunken ear. Souvenir taken for subduing the guilty. The knights called the <name type="ORG">Blades of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name></name> punish the guilt-soaked offenders of the Gods and take this as proof of their conquest. The earless corpses of the guilty will be left behind as a warning to others, inspiring both fear and respect for the Gods. Such is the eternal mandate of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Medal</name><desc>"This faintly warm medal, engraved with the symbol of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>, is the ultimate honor, awarded to shoe who summon the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light and complete a goal. The symbol represents Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn, who lost his deity status and was expunged from the annals. But the old God of War still watches closely over his warriors. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Pendant</name><desc>"This faintly warm medal, engraved with the symbol of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>, is the ultimate honor, awarded to shoe who summon the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light and complete a goal. The symbol represents Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn, who lost his deity status and was expunged from the annals. But the old God of War still watches closely over his warriors. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dragon Head <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name> imbued with the power of the dragons. Rite of apostles of the ancient dragons. Gain head of dragon. Emit dragon breath. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by transformation into an ancient dragon. This rite is only one step, but it cannot be reversed until death. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Dragon Torso <name type="PERSON">Stone</name></name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name> imbued with the power of the dragons. Rite of apostles of the ancient dragons. Gain torso of dragon. Roar like a dragon. The dragon apostles seek transcendence of life itself, attainable by transformation into an ancient dragon. This rite is only one step, but it cannot be reversed until death.   "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Rubbish</name></name><desc><name type="PERSON">Rubbish</name> with no value. Who in their right mind would bother carrying this around? Perhaps you need help.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Copper Coin</name><desc><name type="ORG">"Coin</name> made of copper. Its face shows Old Man McLoyf, god of medicine and drink. Even coins of great value in the world of men have little value in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, where the accepted currency is souls. Those who dream of returning to the outside world are fond of carrying these around."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Silver Coin</name><desc><name type="ORG">"Coin</name> made of silver, with a portrait of the legendary <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal on its face. Even coins of great value in the world of men have little value in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, where the accepted currency is souls. Those who dream of returning to the outside world are fond of carrying these around."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Gold Coin</name><desc><name type="ORG">"Coin</name> made of gold, with <name type="PERSON">Allfather <name type="PERSON">Lloyd</name></name> and his white halo shown on its face. Even coins of great value in the world of men have little value in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, where the accepted currency is souls. Those who dream of returning to the outside world are fond of carrying these around."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Peculiar Doll</name><desc>"A strange doll in strange dress. There once was an abomination who had no place in this world. She clutched this doll tightly, and eventually was drawn into a cold and lonely painted world."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dried Finger</name><desc>"Dried finger with multiple knuckles. Shriveled but still slightly warm. With this many knuckles, surely it cannot belong to anything human."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> Soul</name><desc>"Soul of <name type="ORG">the Ash Maiden</name>, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. <name type="ORG">A <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>'s</name> soul is a draw for humanity, and held within their bosoms, below just a thin layer of skin, are swarms of humanity that writhe and squirm. Was <name type="ORG">the Ash Maiden</name> locked in this dark prison for some transgression, or by her own will?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> Soul</name><desc>"Soul of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>ess, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="ORG">A <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>'s</name> soul is a draw for humanity, and held within their bosoms, below just a thin layer of skin, are swarms of humanity that writhe and squirm. Her brass armor serves to disguise this ghastly form.  "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> Soul</name><desc>"Soul of a <name type="ORG">Daughter of Chaos</name>, <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>'s Domain. <name type="ORG">A <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>'s</name> soul is a draw for humanity, and held within their bosoms, below just a thin layer of skin, are swarms of humanity that writhe and squirm. To her, the countless eggs which appeared were cradles for each tiny humanity."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name> Soul</name><desc>"Soul of a long-lost <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name>. <name type="ORG">Each <name type="ORG">Fire</name> <name type="ORG">Keeper</name></name> is a corporeal manifestation of her bonfire, and a draw for the humanity which is offered to her. Her soul is gnawed by infinite humanity, and can boost the power of precious <name type="ORG">Estus</name> Flasks. Reinforced <name type="ORG">Estus</name> Flasks capture denser <name type="ORG">Estus</name>, allowing for increased restoration of <name type="ORG">HP</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Lost Undead</name><desc>"Soul of a lost Undead who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Soul of a Lost Undead</name><desc>"Large soul of a lost Undead who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Nameless Soldier</name><desc>"Soul of a nameless Undead soldier who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Soul of a Nameless Soldier</name><desc>"Large soul of a nameless Undead soldier who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire many souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Proud <name type="PERSON">Knight</name></name><desc>"Soul of a proud Undead knight who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire many souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Soul of a Proud <name type="PERSON">Knight</name></name><desc>"Large soul of a proud Undead knight who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire many souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Brave <name type="ORG">Warrior</name></name><desc>"Soul of a brave Undead warrior who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire a large amount of souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Soul of a Brave <name type="ORG">Warrior</name></name><desc>"Large soul of a brave Undead warrior who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire a large amount of souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Hero</name><desc>"Soul of a hero of legend who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire a large amount of souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of a Great Hero</name><desc>"Great soul of a hero of legend who has long ago gone <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>. Use to acquire an incredible amount of souls. Souls are the source of all life, and whether Undead, or even <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>, one continues to seek them. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Humanity</name><desc>"Rare tiny black sprite found on corpses. Use to gain 1 humanity and restore a large amount of <name type="ORG">HP</name>. This black sprite is called humanity, but little is known about its true nature. If the soul is the source of all life, then what distinguishes the humanity we hold within ourselves?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Twin Humanities</name><desc>"Rare tiny black sprite found on corpses. Very unusual twin humanity. Use to gain 2 humanity and restore a large amount of <name type="ORG">HP</name>. This black sprite is called humanity, but little is known about its true nature. If the soul is the source of all life, then what distinction is left for humanity?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Hello Carving</name><desc>"Head carved of archtrees by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> in his imprisonment. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> imparts an emotion to each and every completed carving, which helps him achieve personal enlightenment. When a head is disturbed, it speaks, reflecting the emotion conferred to it. This head says \Hello\"". Have another look. Do you sense the amicability in its eyes?"""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Thank you Carving</name><desc>"Head carved of archtrees by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> in his imprisonment. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> imparts an emotion to each and every completed carving, which helps him achieve personal enlightenment. When a head is disturbed, it speaks, reflecting the emotion conferred to it. This head says \Thank you\"". Have another look. Is this not a face of gratitude?"""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Very good! Carving</name><desc>"Head carved of archtrees by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> in his imprisonment. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> imparts an emotion to each and every completed carving, which helps him achieve personal enlightenment. When a head is disturbed, it speaks, reflecting the emotion conferred to it. This head says \Very good!\""Have another look. Does it not appear quite jovial?"""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>I'm sorry Carving</name><desc>"Head carved of archtrees by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> in his imprisonment. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> imparts an emotion to each and every completed carving, which helps him achieve personal enlightenment. When a head is disturbed, it speaks, reflecting the emotion conferred to it. This head says <name type="ORG">\I'm sorry\</name>"". Have another look. Isn't that an expression of atonement?"""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Help me! Carving</name><desc>"Head carved of archtrees by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> in his imprisonment. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> imparts an emotion to each and every completed carving, which helps him achieve personal enlightenment. When a head is disturbed, it speaks, reflecting the emotion conferred to it. This head says \Help me!\""Look again. Can you hear the desperate plea?"""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>, once daughter of the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, but now a chaos demon. Special beings have special souls, and <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>'s soul contains all aspects of Chaos. Use it to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Sif</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Sif</name> the Great Grey Wolf, who guards the grave of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker. Special beings have special souls. Use the soul of <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>, who inherited the divine <name type="ORG">knightsword</name>, to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder"</name><desc>"Soul of the <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light and Cinder, who linked the First Flame. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> bequeathed most of his power to <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> and burned as cinder for the First Flame, but even so, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s soul is a powerful thing indeed."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Core of an Iron Golem</name><desc>"Soul serving as the core of the Iron Golem, guardian of Sen's Fortress, and slayer of countless heroes seeking <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Originally a bone of an everlasting dragon. Use to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, <name type="PERSON">Dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Knight</name></name> who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Special beings have special souls. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> granted this soul to his four most trusted knights. Use to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of the <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Butterfly</name><desc>"Soul of the mystical <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Butterfly, which flitters in <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>. Special beings have special souls. The butterfly's soul is a creation of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Use to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="GPE">Smough</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="GPE">Smough</name> the Executioner, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Special beings have special souls. Use the soul of this eerily gleeful executioner to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name> the Crossbreed, trapped inside the painted world of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name>. Special beings have special souls. Use the soul of this crossbreed bastard child and antithesis to all life to acquire a huge amoung of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin</name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, god of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> and guardian of deserted <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Special beings have special souls. Use the soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn to acquire a huge amount of souls, or to create a unique weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Soul</name><desc>"Soul of <name type="ORG">the white winged lion sanctuary watchkeeper</name>, who dreaded the spread of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. The <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> exhibited traits of several animals other than lions, suggesting that it was no ordinary beast, but rather closer to the beings known as Demons.     "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Soul of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>, who was consumed by the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. The legend that <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> repelled the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> only told half of the story. It seems that he was defeated, and his honor preserved, by some unsung hero, who is the true victor over the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name></name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. This extraordinary soul is a viscous, lukewarm lump of gentle humanity. Ancient <name type="PERSON">Manus</name> was clearly once human. But he became the Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> after his humanity went wild, eternally seeking his precious broken pendant."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. A large, high-quality ember. Handled by the blacksmiths of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Ascension for +5 standard weapon. Allows reinforcement to +10. Also, can ascend <name type="ORG">+5 std <name type="ORG">wpn</name></name> to raw <name type="ORG">wpn</name>. (raw weapon can be reinforced to +5)"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Very Large Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Huge ember of highest quality. Handled by the blacksmiths of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. Ascension for +10 standard weapon. Allows reinforcement to +15, on par with the greatest weapons of legend."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Crystal Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Crystal ember created by <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Handled only by the giant God's blacksmiths. Ascends +10 standard <name type="ORG">wpn</name> to crystal weapon. (crystal weapon can be reinforced to +5) Crystal weapons are powerful but brittle, and cannot be repaired once broken."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Magic Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Large magic ember, a form of sorcery. Handled only by the <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> magic blacksmiths. Ascends +5 magic weapon. Allows reinforcement to +10, the most powerful level for magic weapons."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Enchanted Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. This enchanted ember, a form of sorcery, is a vestige of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Ascends +5 magic <name type="ORG">wpn</name> to enchanted weapon. (enchanted weapon can be reinforced to +5) The sorcerer's enchanted weapon that inflicts magic damage and is boosted by intelligence."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Divine Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Divine embers are property of the church, and intended for divine blacksmiths. Ascends +5 standard <name type="ORG">wpn</name> to divine weapon. (divine weapon can be reinforced to +5) Divine weapons are for Undead hunting. Use against Undead and the pawns of necromancers."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Divine Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Large divine ember, of secret church rites. Intended for select divine blacksmiths. Ascends +5 divine weapon. Allows reinforcement to +10, on par with the very weapons of the Gods."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dark Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. The church long hid the forbidden black ember, and no living blacksmith knows of it. Ascends +5 divine weapon to occult weapon. (occult weapon can be reinforced to +5) Occult weapons were used to hunt <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> and are effective against their followers and kin."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large Flame Ember</name><desc>"Ember required for weapon ascension. Large flame ember used in ancient rites. Handled only by blacksmiths knowledgeable in ancient methods. Ascends +5 fire weapon. Allows reinforcement to +10, the most powerful level for fire weapons.  "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Chaos Flame Ember</name><desc>Ember required for weapon ascension. Chaos Flame Ember is an art of the lost city of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Handled only by blacksmiths knowledgeable in ancient methods. Ascends +5 flame weapon to chaos weapon. (chaos weapon can be reinforced to +5) Chaos weapons are demon weapons augmented by humanity which inflict fire damage.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Shard</name><desc><name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shard for weapon reinforcement. Most common titanite material. Reinforces standard weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shards are fragments of the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name>. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> is etched into weapons to reinforce. </desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Large <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Shard</name><desc><name type="PERSON">"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shard</name> for weapon reinforcement. Larger titanite material. Reinforces standard weapons to +10, and raw weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shards are fragments of the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name>. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> is etched into weapons to reinforce. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Green <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Shard</name><desc><name type="PERSON">"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shard</name> for weapon reinforcement. Green titanite imbued with a special power. Reinforces magic, divine, and fire weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> shards are fragments of the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name>. <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> is etched into weapons to reinforce."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Chunk</name><desc>"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> chunk for weapon reinforcement. Not found outside of <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Reinforces standard weapons to +14, and crystal, lightning weapons to +4. With the discovery of chunks in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the race to locate the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> has begun. But could they be mere myth?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Blue <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Chunk</name><desc>"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> chunk for weapon reinforcement. Blue titanite has powerful magic energy. Reinforces magic weapons to +9, and enchanted weapons to +4. With the discovery of chunks in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the race to locate the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> has begun. But could they be mere myth?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>White <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Chunk</name><desc>"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> chunk for weapon reinforcement. White titanite has powerful miracle energy. Reinforces divine weapons to +9, and occult weapons to +4. With the discovery of chunks in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the race to locate the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> has begun. But could they be mere myth?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Red <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Chunk</name><desc>"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> chunk for weapon reinforcement. Red titanite has powerful fire energy. Reinforces fire weapons to +9, and chaos weapons to +4. With the discovery of chunks in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>, the race to locate the <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> has begun. But could they be mere myth?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Titanite</name> <name type="ORG">Slab</name></name><desc>"<name type="ORG">Titanite</name> slab for weapon reinforcement. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> were the domain of the Gods. Reinforces standard weapons to +15, and crystal or lightning weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> are the heirlooms of a nameless blacksmith deity, who forged the weapons of other Gods. Weapons forged with this slab become rare legendary weapons. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Blue <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> <name type="ORG">Slab</name></name><desc>"Blue titanite slab for weapon reinforcement. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> were the domain of the Gods. Reinforces magic weapons to +10, and enchanted weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> are the heirlooms of a nameless blacksmith deity, who forged the weapons of other Gods. Weapons forged with this slab become rare legendary weapons. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>White <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> <name type="ORG">Slab</name></name><desc>"White titanite slab for weapon reinforcement. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> were the domain of the Gods. Reinforces divine weapons to +10, and occult weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> are the heirlooms of a nameless blacksmith deity, who forged the weapons of other Gods. Weapons forged with this slab become rare legendary weapons. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Red <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> <name type="ORG">Slab</name></name><desc>"Red titanite slab for weapon reinforcement. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> were the domain of the Gods. Reinforces fire weapons to +10, and chaos weapons to +5. <name type="ORG">Legendary <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s</name> are the heirlooms of a nameless blacksmith deity, who forged the weapons of other Gods. Weapons forged with this slab become rare legendary weapons. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dragon Scale</name><desc>"Dragon scale for reinforcing dragon weapons. Peeled from an ancient dragon. A dragon is inseparable from its scales, and the transcendent apostles, who seek the perpetuity of the ancient dragons, have crossed the very end of the earth to seek this invaluable treasure."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Demon <name type="ORG">Titanite</name></name><desc>"Special titanite stolen from a faceless stone beast known as a <name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Demon. When the nameless blacksmith deity passed, from several <name type="ORG">Slab</name>s, great beasts arose. The power of titanite remains within them, and they still roam <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> today."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Twinkling <name type="ORG">Titanite</name></name><desc>"This weapon-reinforcing titanite is imbued with a particularly powerful energy. Reinforces weapons that cannot be reinforced normally to +5. After this titanite was peeled from its <name type="ORG">Slab</name>, it is said that it received a special power, but its specific nature is not clear."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Basement Key</name><desc>"Opens the narrow passage leading below at the far face of the great bridge in the Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name>. The lower Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name> is a treacherous place. Do not turn your back on the wily thieves, or the wild dogs who serve the <name type="PERSON">Capra</name> Demon."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Crest of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"This crest opens a door in <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name> sealed by ancient magic. The door leads to the grave of Sir <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker. Many adventurers have left for the grave, but none have returned, for they make easy prey for local bandits. With such dangers, the crest can do more harm than good in the hands of the uninitiated."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Cage Key</name><desc>"Key to the hanging cage in Sen's Fortress. If a hapless adventurer becomes fatigued during an imprudent attempt to overcome the fortress, the serpent men will not kill him, but lock him up in a lonely cage. Eventually, unless they have forgotten, they drag the victim off to who-knows-where."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name> Cell Key</name><desc>"Key to the cell of the Duke's <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name>. The <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name>, once a trove of precious tomes and letters, became a prison after the onset of Seath's madness. The serpent men who guard the prison know not the value of what they hide. In the basement of the tower are the writhing \mistakes\""of the terrifying experiments which were conducted there."""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name> Giant Door Key</name><desc>"Key to the giant door leading out from the uppermost floor of <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name>, which now serves as a prison. The key's design resembles not the key of a prison; indeed, the tower was once no prison at all, but a trove of precious tomes."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name> Giant Cell Key</name><desc>"Key to the giant cell below the Duke's <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name>. The giant cell once imprisoned countless maidens, but is now empty, save for a few key persons. They struggle to uphold their sanity, as the horde of \mistakes\""writhe at a fearfully close proximity."""</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Blighttown</name> Key</name><desc>"Key to <name type="ORG">Blighttown</name> from the Depths of the Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name>. Swallowed by the Gaping Dragon. As its name suggests, <name type="ORG">Blighttown</name> is a place of great pestilence. Even the polluted inhabitants of the Depths are aware of its dangers, and built this mighty door in hopes that they could remain safely separated."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Key to <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> Ruins</name><desc>"Key to the iron bars separating the ruins of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> and <name type="LOC">Drake Valley</name>. The ruins of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> were blocked off, for the cursed ghosts posed danger to life and spirit, and the legends speak of a terrible Dark which was sealed away."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Annex Key</name><desc>"Key to the annex in the Painted World of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name>. In the wintery painted world, there is a structure resembling an old cathedral; its annex serves as a type of storehouse."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dungeon Cell Key</name><desc>"Key to the dungeon of <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name> to the <name type="LOC">North</name>. A mysterious knight, without saying a word, shoved a corpse down into the cell, and on its person was this key. Who was this knight? And what was his purpose? There may be no answers, but one must still forge ahead."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Big Pilgrim's Key</name><desc>Key to the inner door of <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name> main hall. Big key belonging to a chosen Undead pilgrim. But this Chosen Undead knows not what this pilgrimage has in store.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Undead Asylum F2 <name type="LOC">East</name> Key</name><desc>"Key to the iron bars on the east side of the second floor of the <name type="LOC">North</name> Undead Asylum. <name type="ORG">The Undead Asylum</name> is a giant Undead prison, segmented by countless iron bars. Even if an Undead were to escape from a cell, passage to the outside world would not be gained easily."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Key to the Seal</name><desc>"Key to the floodgates of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>, which seal away the Four Kings who fell to Dark. The Sealers flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to banish the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s and the Four Kings. The agonizing decision was made with the realization that countless lives, and the robust culture of the city, would be lost. The victims now roam the ruins as ghosts."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Key to Depths</name><desc>"Key opening the door from the lower Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name> to the Depths. Those banished from the Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name> eke out their existence in the Depths, a damp lair with no trace of sunlight. Nearly half of the Depths form a perilous flooded labyrinth. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Lift Chamber Key</name><desc>"Key opening the lift leading to <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> ruins in the basement of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Shrine. The ruins of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> were blocked off, for the cursed ghosts posed danger to life and spirit, and the legends speak of a terrible Dark which was sealed away."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Undead Asylum F2 West Key</name><desc>"Key to the iron bars on the west side of the second floor of the <name type="LOC">North</name> Undead Asylum. <name type="ORG">The Undead Asylum</name> is a giant Undead prison, segmented by countless iron bars. But even if a hero found a key in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> to liberate this prison, would he have the means, or the heart, to ever come back?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Mystery Key</name><desc>The purpose of this key is unknown. It appears to be a basic prison cell key.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sewer Chamber Key</name><desc>"Key to the sewer chamber in the Depths. In any community, a few bad apples are sure to exhibit insatiable greed. If they were turned Undead, and banished to the Depths, would they reconsider their ways? Use this key to see for yourself."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Watchtower Basement Key</name><desc>"Key to the basement of the watchtower in the Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name>. The basement of the watchtower forms a stone cell. There are rumors of a hero turned <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> who was locked away by a dear friend. For his own good, of course."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Archive Prison Extra Key</name><desc>"Extra key to a cell in the Duke's <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name>. Perhaps the serpent men were careless, for there are several keys scattered about which fit <name type="FAC">Archive Tower</name> cells."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Residence Key</name><desc>"Key to a residence in the Undead <name type="PERSON">Burg</name>. Simple, sturdy design of the locks in the <name type="PERSON">Burg</name> keep out unwanted visitors. But this is a standard key in these parts, and will open several residences."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="LOC">Crest Key</name></name><desc>"Bent <name type="LOC">Crest Key</name>. The grooves of the crest are enchanted, the door sealed with a powerful spell."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Master Key</name><desc>"This universal key opens any basic lock. Tool of the trade for thieves. But in the cursed land of the Undead, most doors are better left unopened."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Lord Soul</name><desc>"Soul of <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>, first of the dead. <name type="PERSON">This Lord Soul</name> was discovered at the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>. <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name> administers the death of all manner of beings. The power of this soul is so great that it satiates the Lordvessel, despite the fact that much of its energy has already been offered to death."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Lord Soul</name><desc>"Soul of the Bed of Chaos and the mother of all demons. <name type="PERSON">This Lord Soul</name> was found at the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>. The Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> attempted to duplicate the First Flame from a soul, but instead created a distorted being of chaos and fire. Its power formed a bed of life which would become the source of all demons, and is more than enough to satiate the Lordvessel."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Bequeathed Lord Soul Shard</name><desc>"Soul of one of the Four Kings, who fell to Dark. A fragment of a Lord Soul discovered at the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> recognized the foresight of these four great leaders of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>, and granted them their ranks and the fragments of a great soul. Although this is not a full Lord Soul, it can still satiate the Lordvessel."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Bequeathed Lord Soul Shard</name><desc>"Soul of the albino <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. A fragment of a Lord Soul discovered at the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>. Seath allied with Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> and turned upon the dragons, and for this he was awarded Dukedom, embraced by the royalty, and given a fragment of a great soul. Although just a piece, it will still satiate the Lordvessel. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Lordvessel</name><desc>"Lordvessel bestowed upon the chosen Undead who is destined to succeed Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. The chosen Undead is granted the art of warping between bonfires. To open the final door, place this vessel on the <name type="ORG">Fire</name>link Altar, and fill it with powerful souls."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Broken Pendant</name><desc>"Half of a broken stone pendant. The vine appears to originate from <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. A powerful magic can be sensed from this ancient stone. Yet men of this time can neither manipulate nor sense its power, which has a distinct air consisting of both reverence and nostalgia."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Weapon Smithbox</name><desc>Tool used to etch titanite into weapons for reinforcement. Rest at a bonfire to make weapon reinforcement possible.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Armor Smithbox</name><desc>Tool used to etch titanite into armor for reinforcement. Rest at a bonfire to make armor reinforcement possible.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Repairbox</name><desc>"Specialized mortar used to repair weapons and armor by grinding repair powder. Rest at a bonfire to make weapon and armor repair possible. Repair powder is fragile, and cannot be taken along."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Rite of <name type="GPE">Kindling</name></name><desc>"This secret rite allows bonfires to be bolstered further with <name type="GPE">Kindling</name>, so that even more <name type="ORG">Estus</name> can be collected. <name type="GPE">Kindling</name> was a sacred rite passed down among clerics, but all Undead can imitate the process, in the same manner that they restore their <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ing with humanity. How peculiar that humans had found little use for humanity until they turned Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Bottomless Box</name><desc>"A peculiar bottomless wooden box. Its origins are unknown. Some deride it as a symbol of unbridled avarice. Any number of items can be deposited into the box, and items can be managed while resting at a bonfire."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name><desc>"Elementary sorcery. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> soul arrow. Soul arrows inflict magic damage, making them effective against iron armor, tough scales, and other physically resilient materials."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Great <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> strong soul arrow. At the <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, the acquisition of this spell marks an apprentice's coronation as a sorcerer."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name></name><desc>"Soul sorcery emphasizing power. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> heavy soul arrow. A more powerful, but also slower sorcery. Difficult to use due to a long cool down and a limitation on the number of castings."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Great <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> strong heavy soul arrow. As difficult to use as <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name>, but powerful enough to make it well worth it. Adored by certain sorcerers."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Homing Soulmass</name><desc>Sorcery developed by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> homing soulmass. Life originates in the soul; no wonder the soulmass draws toward it. This sorcery is a window into seeker <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s methods.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Homing Crystal Soulmass</name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at <name type="ORG">the Regal Archives</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> homing crystal soulmass. The mysteries of souls, crystals, and the sorceries are deeply intertwined."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Soul Spear</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> piercing soul spear. A symbol of <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s strength, the soul spear is referenced repeatedly in the legends, and is said to be on par with Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lightning."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Crystal Soul Spear</name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at <name type="ORG">the Regal Archives</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> piercing crystal soul spear. These pale magic spears, sharpened through crystallization, are on par with the armaments of the ancient lords."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>Sorcery for casters who wield swords. Magic augmentation: right weapon. The power of the magic swordsmen of <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> is predicated upon this and Magic Shield. Many warriors learn sorcery just for this.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Great <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name>. High magic augmentation: right weapon. At <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, only magic swordsmen on special orders are allowed to learn this spell which grants powerful augmentation to various weapons."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Crystal <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at the Regal Archive. High magic + crystallization: right weapon <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s trials were successful, and the crystal medium facilitated a stronger bond between weapon and soul."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Magic Shield</name><desc>Sorcery for casters who wield swords. Magic augmentation: left shield. <name type="PERSON">Shields</name> augmented by magic are resistant to magic attacks and have higher stability. This spell makes it possible to challenge powerful foes with a small shield.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Strong Magic Shield</name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon Magic Shield. High magic augmentation: left shield. At <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, only magic swordsmen on special orders are allowed to learn this spell which grants temporary strength to <name type="GPE">greatshield</name>s."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Hidden Weapon</name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Turns right weapon invisible. Not a simple augmentation, making it dependent on the skill of its caster. An example of the capacity of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorceries to control light."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: <name type="ORG">Hidden Body</name></name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Turns body nearly invisible. Although perfect invisibility is unachievable due to the risk of dissipation, the caster need only stand still for a moment to blend in to environs with astounding camouflage.   "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Cast Light</name><desc>Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Cast a bright light upon surroundings. This light-producing sorcery is elementary but nonetheless demonstrates the achievements in mysticism of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Such magic has not been developed even in <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name>.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: <name type="PERSON">Hush</name></name><desc>"Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Masks all noises of caster. Effectively, <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> is controlled by the <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, and it is no wonder that the town has its share of dark secrets."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Aural Decoy</name><desc>"Sorcery used by playful sorcerers. Lure enemies away by creating a sound originating in the distance. This spell is not the first choice for serious sorcerers, but it has a surprising amount of applications, some of them extremely effective."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Repair</name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Repair equipped weapons and armor. This sorcery was a part of everyday life in <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Its effects resemble <name type="ORG">Repair Powder</name>, which must have found its way into the culture of this lost land."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Fall Control</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Reduce damage and noise from fall. This sorcery, along with <name type="PERSON">Hush</name>, explains the extravagant cost of hiring <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> spooks.  "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Chameleon</name><desc>Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Transform into something inconspicuous. A separate stealth spell from <name type="ORG">Hidden Body</name>. A skilled stealth sorcerer must be aware of his or her surroundings and of which objects are prime candidates for imitation. </desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Resist Curse</name><desc>"Sorcery of the red-robed remedician. Ingward, guardian of the seal in <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> Sacrifice humanity to undo curse. Abhorrent curses eat away at the core of one's very existence, and cleansing oneself of curses is no easy task indeed."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: Remedy</name><desc>"Sorcery of the red-robed <name type="ORG">Yulva</name>, one of the Sealers of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>. Reduce bleeding and poison build-up, and undo various poisonous effects. One of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>'s unique healing sorceries. Perhaps she abandoned her Sealer duty to take her healing arts back to <name type="ORG">Blighttown</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Sorcery: White Dragon Breath</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> during his infatuation with <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Emit crystal breath of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Although it no longer causes curses, what madness caused old <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> to appropriate this frightful power of the ancient dragons?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name></name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> giant <name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name>. In contrast to standard soul sorceries, <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorceries are weighty and inflict physical damage. Perhaps human souls, because of their humanity, produce sorceries with more tangible presence."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Dark Bead</name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> successive <name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name>s. In contrast to standard soul sorceries, <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorceries are weighty and inflict physical damage. Perhaps a human soul is closer to matter in its humanity."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name></name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. Create a cloud of <name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name>. Although <name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name> is, in theory, relatively close to humanity, it also happens to be a terrible poison for humans. Perhaps it reflects man's cruelty against his own."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Pursuers</name><desc>"Sorcery of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> a fleeting will to the Dark of humanity, and volley the result. The will feels envy, or perhaps love, and despite the inevitably trite and tragic ending, the will sees no alternative, and is driven madly toward its target."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Standard pyromancy of the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Hurl fireball. The fire damage caused by fireballs makes them effective against corporeal beasts and Undead, who by nature fear flame."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Orb</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> which improves upon <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball. Hurl fire orb. The flaming fire orb explodes upon impact, causing fire splash damage in a spectacle which seems to symbolize the strength of the fire-manipulating pyromancers."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Great <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Ultimate fireball pyromancy. Hurl giant fireball. <name type="PERSON">Salaman</name> the Master <name type="PERSON">Pyromancer</name>, also called the Great <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball after this spell, believed pyromancy was rooted in an adoration of fire. Those who acquire this spell usually agree. "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Fire</name>storm</name><desc>"Primal pyromancy taught by <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Erect fire pillars in vicinity. The storm of flame is indiscriminate, and incinerates all nearby life."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Fire</name> Tempest</name><desc>Primal pyromancy of <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Erect giant fire pillars in vicinity. The tempestuous raging flames resemble those summoned by <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name> when they challenged the ancient dragons and scorched the very earth.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Fire</name> Surge</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> foreign to the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Create a surge of flame from palm of hand. Not all pyromancy originates in the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. One hears rumors of unknown pyromancers inhabiting various lands, and this spell is the work of one such outlander."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Fire</name> Whip</name><desc>"Primal pyromancy taught by <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Sweep foes with fire whip. The root pyromancy of <name type="ORG">Combustion</name>, but much more difficult to wield."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: <name type="ORG">Combustion</name></name><desc>"Elementary pyromancy. Create powerful flame in hand. One of the most basic <name type="GPE">pyromancies</name>. For this very reason, the flame thus created is fierce."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Combustion</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> which improves upon <name type="ORG">Combustion</name>. Create powerful, giant flame in hand. Great <name type="ORG">Combustion</name> creates a powerful flame, but many sorcerers mock the simplicity of this spell."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Poison Mist</name><desc>"Unique pyromancy crafted by <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name>, considered a heretic even at the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name> Create poison mist. <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> became an egg-bearing Undead who serves a deformed young girl who speaks an unintelligible tongue."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Toxic Mist</name><desc>"Unique pyromancy crafted by <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name>, considered a heretic even at the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name> Create intense poison mist. Why was <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> driven from the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>? One only need cast this pyromancy, a perverse diversion from the art of fire, to find out."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Acid Surge</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> foreign to the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Emit acid which corrodes weapons and armor. Not all pyromancy originates in the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. One hears rumors of unknown pyromancers inhabiting various lands, and this spell is the work of one such outlander."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Iron Flesh</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Iron flesh boosts defense and resilience. Use of this pyromancy requires caution, as the caster becomes exceedingly heavy and unable to move freely."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Flash Sweat</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Intense sweating reduces flame damage. <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, the most accomplished pupil of <name type="PERSON">Salaman</name> the Master <name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>, pioneered new directions for the art of pyromancy."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Undead Rapport</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Short strength/endurance boost, but lose <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Excessive power eats away the life-force of its caster, and like all dangerous spells, Power Within was kept secret for eons."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Power Within</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters. Hurl giant chaos fireball, which changes strength depending on humanity. The Flame of Chaos can melt stone, producing a short-lived lava glob."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Great Chaos <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters. Erect localized chaos fire pillars which change strength depending on humanity The Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, in an ambitious attempt to copy the First Flame, created instead the Flame of Chaos, a twisted bed of life."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Chaos Storm</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters Sweep foes with chaos fire whip which changes strength depending on humanity The fire whip was wielded by the eldest of <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name>: Chaos <name type="ORG">Fire</name> Whip</name><desc>Miracles</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Black Flame</name><desc>"A pyromancy discovered from the Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> by a pyromancer who wandered into <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Conjure a great black flame in one's palm. Black flames are weighty, and inflict physical damage, enough to smack away the mightiest of shields."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Heal</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Great Heal is a long tale, only learned by a select few. No caster will be disappointed by the bountiful life that it yields."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Great Heal</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Great Heal Excerpt borrows from only several verses of Great Heal. As a result, it can only be cast a stark few times."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Great Heal Excerpt</name><desc>"Special miracle granted to the maidens of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, Princess of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name> for self and vicinity. The miracles of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, the princess cherished by all, grant their blessing to a great many warriors."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Soothing <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light</name><desc>"Common miracle amongst cleric knights. <name type="ORG">Gradual <name type="ORG">HP</name></name> restoration. Beware of the cleric knight blessed by Replenishment, for he shall not fall easily."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Replenishment</name><desc>"Special miracle granted to the maidens of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, Princess of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. <name type="ORG">Gradual <name type="ORG">HP</name></name> restoration for self and vicinity. The miracles of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, the princess cherished by all, grant their blessing to a great many warriors."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Bountiful <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light</name><desc>"Miracle known only by the servants of the first dead, <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>. <name type="PERSON">Giant <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> swords jut</name> out in vicinity. <name type="ORG">Nito</name> sleeps deep within <name type="FAC">the Giant Catacombs</name>, quietly overseeing all death, and waiting for his servants to usher in the Eye of Death."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> Sword Dance</name><desc>"Miracle known only by the servants of the first dead, <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>. <name type="PERSON">Giant <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> swords jut</name> out in vicinity. Many have died, and many eyes were claimed to realize the Greatsword Dance, a <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> ritual known only by his closest servants."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> Greatsword Dance</name><desc>"Lost miracle, foreign to <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> While active, no losses incurred upon death The Way of White recognizes death itself, but admonishes the Undead. It is for this very reason that this miracle was lost."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Escape Death</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Return to last bonfire rested at. Would normally link to one's homeland, only the curse of the Undead has distorted its power, redirecting casters to a bonfire. Or perhaps for Undead, this serves as home?"</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Homeward</name><desc>"Common miracle amongst cleric knights. Create shockwave. This quickly-acting miracle inflicts no damage, but propels foes back and defends against arrows. Cleric knights use this miracle when charging into enemy mobs.   "</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="ORG">Force</name></name><desc>Primal form of <name type="ORG">Force</name>. Create powerful shockwave. Wrath of the Gods was an epic tale that tattered over time and devolved into the modern <name type="ORG">Force</name>. This primal form of <name type="ORG">Force</name> emits a shockwave that also inflicts damage.</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Wrath of the Gods</name><desc>"Outland miracle, foreign to <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>. Emit shockwave. Considered an alternate branching of <name type="ORG">Force</name>. Emits an expanding shockwave orb."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Emit <name type="ORG">Force</name></name><desc>"Miracle of clerics on an Undead mission. Display more guidance from other worlds. Guidance facilitates communication between Undead, but their value varies greatly. A balance of faith and wisdom is required."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Seek Guidance</name><desc>"Miracle passed down to those bound by the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light covenant. Hurl lightning spear. Lightning spears inflict rare lightning damage, and are very effective against magic, fire, and most of all, dragons."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Lightning Spear</name><desc>"Miracle passed down to those bound by the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light covenant. Hurl giant lightning spear. The weapon of the God of War, who inherited the sunlight of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, but had respect only for arms, and nothing else."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Great Lightning Spear</name><desc>"Miracle born from the fading soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. Hurl sunlight spear. In the war that marked the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> wielded these rays of sunlight, which remain fierce even as they fade."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Spear</name><desc>"Miracle of <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> the Rock. Cover body in defensive magic coating. This coating greatly boosts magic defense, assisting warriors who must face the magic which <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> countered so proficiently."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Magic Barrier</name><desc>"Miracle of <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> the Rock. Cover body in powerful def. magic coating. <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock, an old battlefield compatriot of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, was the sworn enemy of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. He despised magic, and made certain to devise means of counteraction."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Great Magic Barrier</name><desc>"Miracle of the black-haired witch <name type="ORG">Velka</name>. Temporary auto counter vs. heavy damage. For each sin there is a punishment, and it is the task of <name type="ORG">Goddess <name type="ORG">Velka</name></name> to define the sin, and mete out the punishment."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Karmic Justice</name><desc>"Miracle of the black-haired witch <name type="ORG">Velka</name>. Temporary auto counter vs. heavy damage. For each sin there is a punishment, and it is the task of <name type="ORG">Goddess <name type="ORG">Velka</name></name> to define the sin, and mete out the punishment."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Tranquil Walk of Peace</name><desc>"Secret rite of the black-haired witch <name type="ORG">Velka</name>. Prevents casting of magic within effect area. <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin, is a rogue deity, but she is versed in arts both new and old, and is considered to have a great range of influence even as gods are concerned."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: Vow of Silence</name><desc>"Miracle wielded by Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn. Boost right weapon with rays of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. The power of sunlight, manifested as lightning, is very effective against dragons. When the eldest son was stripped of his deific status, he left this on his father's coffin, perhaps as a final farewell."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Blade</name><desc>"Miracle granted to those bound by covenant to <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn. Boost right weapon with rays of <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>. The power of the rays of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> are manifested in vengeance, and the deeper the animus, the more devastating the attack."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Miracle: <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Blade</name><desc>"Miracle granted to those bound by covenant to <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn. Boost right weapon with rays of <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>. The power of the rays of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> are manifested in vengeance, and the deeper the animus, the more devastating the attack."</desc>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Beckon</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Point forward</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Hurrah!</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Bow</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Joy</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Shrug</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Wave</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Praise the <name type="ORG">Sun</name></name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Point up</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Point down</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Look skyward</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Well! What is it!</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Prostration</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Proper bow</name>
<itemType>Item</itemType><name>Prayer</name>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s Ring</name><desc>"This ring was named after <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s old battlefield compatriot. <name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s men wore the ring to express faith in their leader and to carry a heavier load."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Red Tearstone Ring</name><desc>The rare gem called tearstone has the uncanny ability to sense imminent death. This red tearstone from <name type="PERSON">Carim</name> boosts the attack of its wearer when in danger.</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Blade Covenant Ring</name><desc>"Ring granted to those bound by the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Blade covenant. Answer Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin's summoning. <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, all too aware of his repulsive, frail appearance, created the illusion of a sister <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, who helps him guard over <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. An unmasking of these deities would be tantamount to blasphemy."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Cat Covenant Ring</name><desc>Ring granted to those bound by the Forest <name type="PERSON">Hunter</name> covenant. Answer <name type="PERSON">Alvina</name>'s summoning. The white cat <name type="PERSON">Alvina</name> speaks a human tongue and has lived since the early Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>. <name type="PERSON">Alvina</name> was a trusted friend of <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> and the Great Wolf <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>.</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Cloranthy Ring</name><desc>"This ancient ring, engraved with a large green flower, is of unknown origin. Hastens the regeneration of stamina."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Flame <name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plate Ring</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plates, the symbol of a true knight, grant the strength to face various hardships. The red stoneplate symbolizes fire, and boosts defence against flame."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Thunder <name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plate Ring</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plates, the symbol of a true knight, grant the strength to face various hardships. The yellow stoneplate symbolizes thunder, and boosts defence against lightning."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Spell <name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plate Ring</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plates, the symbol of a true knight, grant the strength to face various hardships. The blue stoneplate symbolizes souls, and boosts defence against magic."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Speckled <name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plate Ring</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Stone</name>plates, the symbol of a true knight, grant the strength to face various hardships. The precious rare speckled stoneplate grants a small boost to defence against magic, flame, and lightning."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Bloodbite Ring</name><desc>"One of the infamous bite rings commissioned by Sir <name type="PERSON">Arstor</name> of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>. Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset, in its ability to help prevent bleeding."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Poisonbite Ring</name><desc>"One of the infamous bite rings commissioned by Sir <name type="PERSON">Arstor</name> of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>. Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset, in its ability to help prevent poison."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Tiny Being's Ring</name><desc>"Ring made of an ancient tiny red jewel. <name type="PERSON">Grant</name>s small increase to <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Rings grant powers large and small. Their discovery, and effective use, can make one's journey easier."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Cursebite Ring</name><desc>"One of the infamous bite rings commissioned by Sir <name type="PERSON">Arstor</name> of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>. Despite the dreadful rumors surrounding its creation, this ring is an unmistakable asset, in its ability to help prevent curses."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>White Seance Ring</name><desc>"A divine ring entrusted to the head bishop of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> and apostle to <name type="PERSON">Allfather <name type="PERSON">Lloyd</name></name>, uncle to Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. It grants additional attunement slots. The head bishop of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> is the guardian of law and caste, and one of the great royals of <name type="PERSON">Thorolund</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Bellowing Dragoncrest Ring</name><desc>"A special ring granted to only the most accomplished sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The ring is engraved with an everlasting dragon, and boosts the strength of sorceries."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Dusk Crown Ring</name><desc>"This magic crown-shaped ring was granted to princess Dusk of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> upon her birth. The ringstone allows its wearer to cast additional sorceries, but at the cost of one-half of <name type="ORG">HP</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Hornet Ring</name><desc>"One of the special rings granted to the four knights of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. <name type="ORG">The Hornet Ring</name> belonged to the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>. By boosting critical attacks, its wearer can annihilate foes, as <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name>'s dagger laid waste to Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Hawk Ring</name><desc>"One of the special rings granted to the four knights of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. <name type="ORG">The Hawk Ring</name> belonged to Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, who led the <name type="ORG">Greatarchers</name>. Boosts bow range, so that arrows fly like they were shot by <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s great bow, which took down high-flying dragons."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Steel Protection</name><desc>"This ring belonged to the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal. It grants its wearer protection by boosting defense against physical attacks. Of the many legends surrounding the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, one of the more well-known speaks of his standing down a giant <name type="PERSON">drake</name> and slashing it to pieces."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Covetous Gold Serpent Ring</name><desc>"The serpent is an imperfect dragon and symbol of the Undead. Its habit of devouring prey even larger than itself has led to an association with gluttony. This gold ring, engraved with the serpent, boosts its wearer's item discovery, so that more items can be amassed."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Covetous Silver Serpent Ring</name><desc>"The serpent is an imperfect dragon and symbol of the Undead. Its habit of devouring prey even larger than itself has led to an association with gluttony. This silver ring, engraved with the serpent, rewards its wearer with additional souls for each kill."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Slumbering Dragoncrest Ring</name><desc>"This ring was secretly worn by a certain surreptitious sorcerer at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The ring is engraved with an everlasting dragon in silent slumber, and masks all sound emitting from its wearer."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Fog</name><desc>"Those who befriend <name type="PERSON">Alvina</name> are given this mysterious ring. It resembles a pearl with its robust pure-white fog. The ring camouflages its wearer's presence, helping to prevent detection."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Rusted Iron Ring</name><desc>"This iron ring was used to shackle the guilty. It is terribly rusted, and faintly stained with blood. Those who find this strange ring to their liking will be pleased to find it easier to gain footing on poor ground such as swamps."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Sacrifice</name><desc>"This mystical ring was created in a sacrificial rite of <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. Its wearer will lose nothing upon death, but the ring itself breaks."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Rare Ring of Sacrifice</name><desc>"This mystical ring was created in a sacrificial rite of <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. The magenta-shaded ring is especially rare. Its wearer will lose nothing upon death, and will be freed from any curse whatsoever, but the ring itself breaks."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Dark Wood Grain Ring</name><desc>"This special ring crafted in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land is made of gold, but with a wood grain crest on its surface. Agents of subterfuge in this faraway land are particularly fond of the dark gold wood grain, which greatly alters its wearer's rolling action."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name> Princess</name><desc>"This ring is granted to those who enter a Covenant with <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, daughter of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> and the Princess of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. This slightly warm ring boosts the synergy of miracles. The Princess of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere left <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> along with many other deities, and later became wife to Flame God Flann."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Condemnation</name><desc>"This black diamond ring is granted to those who enter a Covenant with <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin. It automatically counterattacks when its wearer inflicts sustained damage. <name type="ORG">Velka</name> the Goddess of Sin is an eccentric witch versed in various secret rites, an"</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Blind Ghosts</name><desc>"This ring belonged to the seal guardian of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>. It prevents its wearer's discovery by cursed ghosts. There were once three guardians of the seal, but two of them tired of their eternal task, and left <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> long ago."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Old Witch's Ring</name><desc>"Old ring from an old witch. Engraved minutely with indecipherable script, but seemingly useless."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Covenant of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"This ring symbolizes <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>'s covenant with the beasts of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. Its wearer, like <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> himself, can traverse the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Orange Charred Ring</name><desc>"An orange ring enchanted by a witch. Reduces lava damage. Since his sores were inflamed by lava from birth, his witch sisters gave him this special ring. But fool that he is, he readily dropped it, and from that spot, a terrible centipede demon was born."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Displacement</name><desc>"The ring of a lost miracle of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>. This ring takes damage in place of its wearer, but has a fixed chance of breaking. As evidenced by this ring, the culture of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> was unique, and its flooding is widely considered to be a great loss."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Lingering Dragoncrest Ring</name><desc>"A special ring granted to only the most accomplished sorcerers at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. The ring is engraved with a lingering dragon, and boosts the length of the effects of sorceries."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of the Evil Eye</name><desc>"According to legend, this ring contains the spirit of the evil eye, a dark beast which assaulted <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. The strength of the evil eye does not waver, and <name type="ORG">HP</name> is absorbed from fallen enemies."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of Favor and Protection</name><desc>"A ring symbolizing the favor and protection of the goddess <name type="ORG">Fina</name>, known in legend to possess \fateful beauty.\"" This ring boosts its wearer's <name type="ORG">HP</name>, stamina, and max equipment load, but breaks if ever removed."""</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Leo Ring</name><desc>One of the special rings granted to the four knights of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. <name type="PERSON">The Leo Ring</name> belonged to <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name> the Dragonslayer. This ring strengthens counters with pierce weapons. His lugged spear is said to have sliced a boulder in two.</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name> Wood Grain Ring</name><desc>"This special ring crafted in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land is made of gold, but with a wood grain crest on its surface. The ring slows the loss of weapon durability and is particularly useful to bearers of delicate swords crafted in the <name type="LOC">East</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Wolf Ring</name><desc>"One of the special rings granted to the four knights of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. <name type="ORG">The Wolf Ring</name> belongs to <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker. <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> had an unbendable will of steel, and was unmatched with a greatsword. "</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Blue Tearstone Ring</name><desc>The rare gem called tearstone has the uncanny ability to sense imminent death. This blue tearstone from <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name> boosts the defence of its wearer when in danger.</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Ring of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>'s Firstborn</name><desc>"Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn, who inherited the sunlight, once wore this ancient ring. Boosts the strength of miracles. Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn was a god of war, but his foolishness led to a loss of the annals, and rescinding of his deific status. Today, even his name is not known."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Seance Ring</name><desc>"This ring is granted to adherents of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> deity and last born of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. <name type="PERSON">Grant</name>s additional magic attunement slots. The Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin is the only remaining deity in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. His followers are few, but their tasks are of vital importance."</desc>
<itemType>Ring</itemType><name>Calamity Ring</name><desc>"A ring enchanted by the orange eye of <name type="PERSON">Kalameet</name>, the bringer of calamity. Doubles damage received by its wearer. A useless ring befitting of no finger. Best left unknown, or at least well hidden."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name><desc>"Elementary sorcery. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> soul arrow. Soul arrows inflict magic damage, making them effective against iron armor, tough scales, and other physically resilient materials."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> strong soul arrow. At the <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, the acquisition of this spell marks an apprentice's coronation as a sorcerer."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name></name><desc>"Soul sorcery emphasizing power. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> heavy soul arrow. A more powerful, but also slower sorcery. Difficult to use due to a long cool down and a limitation on the number of castings."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> strong heavy soul arrow. As difficult to use as <name type="ORG">Heavy <name type="ORG">Soul Arrow</name></name>, but powerful enough to make it well worth it. Adored by certain sorcerers."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Homing Soulmass</name><desc>Sorcery developed by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> homing soulmass. Life originates in the soul; no wonder the soulmass draws toward it. This sorcery is a window into seeker <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s methods.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Homing Crystal Soulmass</name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at <name type="ORG">the Regal Archives</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> homing crystal soulmass. The mysteries of souls, crystals, and the sorceries are deeply intertwined."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Soul Spear</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> piercing soul spear. A symbol of <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s strength, the soul spear is referenced repeatedly in the legends, and is said to be on par with Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lightning."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Crystal Soul Spear</name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at <name type="ORG">the Regal Archives</name>. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> piercing crystal soul spear. These pale magic spears, sharpened through crystallization, are on par with the armaments of the ancient lords."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>Sorcery for casters who wield swords. Magic augmentation: right weapon. The power of the magic swordsmen of <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> is predicated upon this and Magic Shield. Many warriors learn sorcery just for this.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name>. High magic augmentation: right weapon. At <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, only magic swordsmen on special orders are allowed to learn this spell which grants powerful augmentation to various weapons."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Crystal <name type="ORG">Magic Weapon</name></name><desc>"Sorcery boosted by the knowledge. <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> acquired at the Regal Archive. High magic + crystallization: right weapon <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s trials were successful, and the crystal medium facilitated a stronger bond between weapon and soul."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Magic Shield</name><desc>Sorcery for casters who wield swords. Magic augmentation: left shield. <name type="PERSON">Shields</name> augmented by magic are resistant to magic attacks and have higher stability. This spell makes it possible to challenge powerful foes with a small shield.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Strong Magic Shield</name><desc>"Sorcery which improves upon Magic Shield. High magic augmentation: left shield. At <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, only magic swordsmen on special orders are allowed to learn this spell which grants temporary strength to <name type="GPE">greatshield</name>s."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Hidden Weapon</name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Turns right weapon invisible. Not a simple augmentation, making it dependent on the skill of its caster. An example of the capacity of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorceries to control light."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Hidden Body</name></name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Turns body nearly invisible. Although perfect invisibility is unachievable due to the risk of dissipation, the caster need only stand still for a moment to blend in to environs with astounding camouflage.   "</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Cast Light</name><desc>Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Cast a bright light upon surroundings. This light-producing sorcery is elementary but nonetheless demonstrates the achievements in mysticism of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Such magic has not been developed even in <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name>.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hush</name></name><desc>"Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Masks all noises of caster. Effectively, <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> is controlled by the <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>, and it is no wonder that the town has its share of dark secrets."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Aural Decoy</name><desc>"Sorcery used by playful sorcerers. Lure enemies away by creating a sound originating in the distance. This spell is not the first choice for serious sorcerers, but it has a surprising amount of applications, some of them extremely effective."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Repair</name><desc>"Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Repair equipped weapons and armor. This sorcery was a part of everyday life in <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Its effects resemble <name type="ORG">Repair Powder</name>, which must have found its way into the culture of this lost land."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Fall Control</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by a certain surreptitious sorcerer at <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. Reduce damage and noise from fall. This sorcery, along with <name type="PERSON">Hush</name>, explains the extravagant cost of hiring <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> spooks.  "</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Chameleon</name><desc>Ancient sorcery of the lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Transform into something inconspicuous. A separate stealth spell from <name type="ORG">Hidden Body</name>. A skilled stealth sorcerer must be aware of his or her surroundings and of which objects are prime candidates for imitation.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Resist Curse</name><desc>"Sorcery of the red-robed remedician. Ingward, guardian of the seal in <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> Sacrifice humanity to undo curse. Abhorrent curses eat away at the core of one's very existence, and cleansing oneself of curses is no easy task indeed."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Remedy</name><desc>"Sorcery of the red-robed <name type="ORG">Yulva</name>, one of the Sealers of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>. Reduce bleeding and poison build-up, and undo various poisonous effects. One of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>'s unique healing sorceries. Perhaps she abandoned her Sealer duty to take her healing arts back to <name type="ORG">Blighttown</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>White Dragon Breath</name><desc>"Sorcery developed by <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> during his infatuation with <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Emit crystal breath of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Although it no longer causes curses, what madness caused old <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> to appropriate this frightful power of the ancient dragons?"</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name></name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> giant <name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name>. In contrast to standard soul sorceries, <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorceries are weighty and inflict physical damage. Perhaps human souls, because of their humanity, produce sorceries with more tangible presence."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Dark Bead</name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. <name type="ORG">Fire</name> successive <name type="PERSON">Dark Orb</name>s. In contrast to standard soul sorceries, <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorceries are weighty and inflict physical damage. Perhaps a human soul is closer to matter in its humanity."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name></name><desc>"<name type="FAC">Abyss</name> sorcery discovered by an <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcerer on the brink of madness. Create a cloud of <name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name>. Although <name type="PERSON">Dark Fog</name> is, in theory, relatively close to humanity, it also happens to be a terrible poison for humans. Perhaps it reflects man's cruelty against his own."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Pursuers</name><desc>"Sorcery of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. <name type="PERSON">Grant</name> a fleeting will to the Dark of humanity, and volley the result. The will feels envy, or perhaps love, and despite the inevitably trite and tragic ending, the will sees no alternative, and is driven madly toward its target."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Standard pyromancy of the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Hurl fireball. The fire damage caused by fireballs makes them effective against corporeal beasts and Undead, who by nature fear flame."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Orb</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> which improves upon <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball. Hurl fire orb. The flaming fire orb explodes upon impact, causing fire splash damage in a spectacle which seems to symbolize the strength of the fire-manipulating pyromancers."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Ultimate fireball pyromancy. Hurl giant fireball. <name type="PERSON">Salaman</name> the Master <name type="PERSON">Pyromancer</name>, also called the Great <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball after this spell, believed pyromancy was rooted in an adoration of fire. Those who acquire this spell usually agree. "</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name>storm</name><desc>"Primal pyromancy taught by <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Erect fire pillars in vicinity. The storm of flame is indiscriminate, and incinerates all nearby life."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Tempest</name><desc>Primal pyromancy of <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Erect giant fire pillars in vicinity. The tempestuous raging flames resemble those summoned by <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name> when they challenged the ancient dragons and scorched the very earth.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Surge</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> foreign to the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Create a surge of flame from palm of hand. Not all pyromancy originates in the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. One hears rumors of unknown pyromancers inhabiting various lands, and this spell is the work of one such outlander."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Whip</name><desc>"Primal pyromancy taught by <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Sweep foes with fire whip. The root pyromancy of <name type="ORG">Combustion</name>, but much more difficult to wield."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Combustion</name></name><desc>"Elementary pyromancy. Create powerful flame in hand. One of the most basic <name type="GPE">pyromancies</name>. For this very reason, the flame thus created is fierce."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great <name type="ORG">Combustion</name></name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> which improves upon <name type="ORG">Combustion</name>. Create powerful, giant flame in hand. Great <name type="ORG">Combustion</name> creates a powerful flame, but many sorcerers mock the simplicity of this spell."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Poison Mist</name><desc>"Unique pyromancy crafted by <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name>, considered a heretic even at the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name> Create poison mist. <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> became an egg-bearing Undead who serves a deformed young girl who speaks an unintelligible tongue."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Toxic Mist</name><desc>"Unique pyromancy crafted by <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name>, considered a heretic even at the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name> Create intense poison mist. Why was <name type="ORG">Eingyi</name> driven from the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>? One only need cast this pyromancy, a perverse diversion from the art of fire, to find out."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Acid Surge</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> foreign to the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. Emit acid which corrodes weapons and armor. Not all pyromancy originates in the <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name>. One hears rumors of unknown pyromancers inhabiting various lands, and this spell is the work of one such outlander."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Iron Flesh</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Iron flesh boosts defense and resilience. Use of this pyromancy requires caution, as the caster becomes exceedingly heavy and unable to move freely."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Flash Sweat</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Intense sweating reduces flame damage. <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, the most accomplished pupil of <name type="PERSON">Salaman</name> the Master <name type="PERSON">Pyromancer</name>, pioneered new directions for the art of pyromancy."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Undead Rapport</name><desc>"Advanced pyromancy of <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>. Charm Undead and gain temporary allies. The living are lured by flame, and this relationship is part and parcel to the art of pyromancy. Can be used by either gender."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Power Within</name><desc>"<name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> of <name type="ORG">Carmina</name>, who harnessed the power of flame to actualize the inner-self. Short strength/endurance boost, but lose <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Excessive power eats away the life-force of its caster, and like all dangerous spells, Power Within was kept secret for eons."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great Chaos <name type="ORG">Fire</name>ball</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters. Hurl giant chaos fireball, which changes strength depending on humanity. The Flame of Chaos can melt stone, producing a short-lived lava glob."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Chaos Storm</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters. Erect localized chaos fire pillars which change strength depending on humanity. The Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, in an ambitious attempt to copy the First Flame, created instead the Flame of Chaos, a twisted bed of life."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Chaos <name type="ORG">Fire</name> Whip</name><desc>"Art of the Flame of Chaos, which engulfed the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> and her daughters. Sweep foes with chaos fire whip which changes strength depending on humanity. The fire whip was wielded by the eldest of <name type="ORG">the Daughters of Chaos</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Black Flame</name><desc>"A pyromancy discovered from the Dark of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name> by a pyromancer who wandered into <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Conjure a great black flame in one's palm. Black flames are weighty, and inflict physical damage, enough to smack away the mightiest of shields."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Heal</name><desc>"Elementary miracle cast by clerics. Restores <name type="ORG">HP</name>. To cast a miracle, the caster learns a tale of <name type="GPE">the Gods,</name> and says a prayer to be blessed by its revelations. Heal is the shortest of such miraculous tales."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great Heal</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Great Heal is a long tale, only learned by a select few. No caster will be disappointed by the bountiful life that it yields."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great Heal Excerpt</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name>. Great Heal Excerpt borrows from only several verses of Great Heal. As a result, it can only be cast a stark few times."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Soothing <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light</name><desc>"Special miracle granted to the maidens of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, Princess of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. Restores high <name type="ORG">HP</name> for self and vicinity. The miracles of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, the princess cherished by all, grant their blessing to a great many warriors."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Replenishment</name><desc>"Common miracle amongst cleric knights. <name type="ORG">Gradual <name type="ORG">HP</name></name> restoration. Beware of the cleric knight blessed by Replenishment, for he shall not fall easily."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Bountiful <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light</name><desc>"Special miracle granted to the maidens of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, Princess of the <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. <name type="ORG">Gradual <name type="ORG">HP</name></name> restoration for self and vicinity. The miracles of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere, the princess cherished by all, grant their blessing to a great many warriors."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> Sword Dance</name><desc>"Miracle known only by the servants of the first dead, <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>. <name type="PERSON">Giant <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> swords jut</name> out in vicinity. <name type="ORG">Nito</name> sleeps deep within <name type="FAC">the Giant Catacombs</name>, quietly overseeing all death, and waiting for his servants to usher in the Eye of Death."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> Greatsword Dance</name><desc>"Miracle known only by the servants of the first dead, <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>. <name type="PERSON">Giant <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> swords jut</name> out in vicinity. Many have died, and many eyes were claimed to realize the Greatsword Dance, a <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> ritual known only by his closest servants."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Escape Death</name><desc>"Lost miracle, foreign to <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name> While active, no losses incurred upon death The Way of White recognizes death itself, but admonishes the Undead. It is for this very reason that this miracle was lost."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Homeward</name><desc>"Great miracle cast by advanced clerics. Return to last bonfire rested at. Would normally link to one's homeland, only the curse of the Undead has distorted its power, redirecting casters to a bonfire. Or perhaps for Undead, this serves as home?"</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Force</name></name><desc>"Common miracle amongst cleric knights. Create shockwave. This quickly-acting miracle inflicts no damage, but propels foes back and defends against arrows. Cleric knights use this miracle when charging into enemy mobs.   "</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Wrath of the Gods</name><desc>Primal form of <name type="ORG">Force</name>. Create powerful shockwave. Wrath of the Gods was an epic tale that tattered over time and devolved into the modern <name type="ORG">Force</name>. This primal form of <name type="ORG">Force</name> emits a shockwave that also inflicts damage.</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Emit <name type="ORG">Force</name></name><desc>"Outland miracle, foreign to <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>. Emit shockwave. Considered an alternate branching of <name type="ORG">Force</name>. Emits an expanding shockwave orb."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Seek Guidance</name><desc>"Miracle of clerics on an Undead mission. Display more guidance from other worlds. Guidance facilitates communication between Undead, but their value varies greatly. A balance of faith and wisdom is required."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Lightning Spear</name><desc>"Miracle passed down to those bound by the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light covenant. Hurl lightning spear. Lightning spears inflict rare lightning damage, and are very effective against magic, fire, and most of all, dragons."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great Lightning Spear</name><desc>"Miracle passed down to those bound by the <name type="ORG">Warrior</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light covenant. Hurl giant lightning spear. The weapon of the God of War, who inherited the sunlight of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, but had respect only for arms, and nothing else."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Spear</name><desc>"Miracle born from the fading soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>. Hurl sunlight spear. In the war that marked the dawn of the Age of <name type="ORG">Fire</name>, <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> wielded these rays of sunlight, which remain fierce even as they fade."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Magic Barrier</name><desc>"Miracle of <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> the Rock. Cover body in defensive magic coating. This coating greatly boosts magic defense, assisting warriors who must face the magic which <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> countered so proficiently."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Great Magic Barrier</name><desc>"Miracle of <name type="ORG">Bishop <name type="GPE">Havel</name></name> the Rock. Cover body in powerful def. magic coating. <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock, an old battlefield compatriot of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, was the sworn enemy of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. He despised magic, and made certain to devise means of counteraction."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Karmic Justice</name><desc>"Miracle of the black-haired witch <name type="ORG">Velka</name>. Temporary auto counter vs. heavy damage. For each sin there is a punishment, and it is the task of <name type="ORG">Goddess <name type="ORG">Velka</name></name> to define the sin, and mete out the punishment."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Tranquil Walk of Peace</name><desc>"Outland miracle, foreign to <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>. Slows all walking within effect area. This miracle is normally used to flee, as it slows walking but does not affect attacks, but nevertheless defines peace perfectly."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name>Vow of Silence</name><desc>"Secret rite of the black-haired witch <name type="ORG">Velka</name>. Prevents casting of magic within effect area. <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, the Goddess of Sin, is a rogue deity, but she is versed in arts both new and old, and is considered to have a great range of influence even as gods are concerned."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Blade</name><desc>"Miracle wielded by Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s firstborn. Boost right weapon with rays of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>. The power of sunlight, manifested as lightning, is very effective against dragons. When the eldest son was stripped of his deific status, he left this on his father's coffin, perhaps as a final farewell."</desc>
<itemType>Spell</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Blade</name><desc>"Miracle granted to those bound by covenant to <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn. Boost right weapon with rays of <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name>. The power of the rays of the <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> are manifested in vengeance, and the deeper the animus, the more devastating the attack."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dagger</name><desc>"Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash/Thrust This standard small dagger has only a modest attack but can be jabbed in rapid succession, and is effective in critical hits such as after a parry or when stabbing in the back. With both slash and thrust attacks, this dagger is useful in various situations."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Parry</name>ing Dagger</name><desc>"Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash/Thrust This dagger is useful after parrying and is normally equipped in the left hand. A favorite of the knights of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>, who are famous for fighting without a shield."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Ghost Blade</name><desc>Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash/Thrust The ghosts of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> clutch this wickedly sharp dagger with their bony hands and make mincemeat of the living. One of the cursed weapons which can inflict damage upon ghosts. </desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Bandit's Knife</name><desc>"Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash This wide single-edged shortsword is the favorite of lowly thieves and bandits. Primarily a slicing weapon, but highly effective when used for critical hits, such as after parrying or from behind."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name>'s Dagger</name><desc>"Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons, came from the tail of <name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name>, the Dragon Crossbreed in the painted world of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name>. Possessing the power of lifehunt, it dances about when wielded, in a fashion reminiscent of the white-robed painting guardians."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Shortsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust This small straight sword is widely used, to an extent only matched by the longsword. An accessible sword which inflicts consistent regular damage and high slash damage, making it applicable to a variety of situations."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Longsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Widely-used standard straight sword, only matched in ubiquity by the shortsword. An accessible sword which inflicts consistent regular damage and high slash damage, making it applicable to a variety of situations."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Broadsword</name><desc>Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular The wide blade of this straight sword emphasizes slicing and has no thrust attack. The horizontal sweeping motion makes this sword effective against multiple enemies.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Broken Straight Sword</name><desc>Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Half of the blade of this straight sword is broken off. Only the completely <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name>ed would even consider using this as a weapon.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Side Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust The knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> wielded these rock-solid, long swords which are excellent for thrust attacks. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the home of <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but the kingdom was reduced to ruins after a widespread outbreak of Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Straight Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust This standard longsword, belonging to <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, is of high quality, is well- forged, and has been kept in good repair. Easy-to-use and dependable, but unlikely to live up to its grandiose name."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Barbed Straight Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Thrust The choice weapon of the infamous <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name> <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, also known as the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns for the gnarly spikes on his favorite weapon. This frightful sword deals only thrust attacks, and causes heavy bleeding."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Silv. <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Str. Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular The silver knights of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> guard the city using this beautifully slender weapon. Its chain attacks, in which the wielder takes great advancing steps and makes use of his bodyweight, are deadly even in single hits."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Astora</name>'s Straight Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Straight sword of an unknown knight, likely one of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>'s superiors. High-quality weapon with a powerful blessing."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Darksword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular The sword of the knights of the Four Kings of <name type="GPE">New Londo</name>. Its blade is wide and thick, and it is wielded in an unusual manner. When the Four Kings were seduced by evil, their knights became <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, servants of the Dark who wielded these darkswords. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Drake Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons, is formed by a <name type="PERSON">drake</name>'s tail. Drakes are seen as undeveloped imitators of the dragons, but in they are likely their distant kin. The sword is imbued with a mystical power, to be released when held with both hands."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Straight Sword Hilt</name><desc>"Weapon type: Straight Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust The hilt of this lost sword was found discarded in <name type="FAC">the Undead Asylum</name>. Only slightly better than one's bare hands, and not recommended for extensive use. Be certain to find a replacement quickly."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Bastard Sword</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular This standard greatsword is normally wielded with two hands due to its great weight. Usually swung in large arcs and effective against multiple foes. Far from ideal when fighting in tight quarters.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Claymore</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust This larger type of greatsword is normally wielded with two hands due to its weight. This highly flexible greatsword can be used to attack in swings or thrusts.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Man-serpent Greatsword</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular This single-bladed blood-stained greatsword is the choice weapon of the slithering serpent men of Sen's Fortress. An ordinary human will have great difficulty swinging this heavy beast effectively.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Flamberge</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Slash This greatsword with an undulating blade is the choice weapon of the slithering serpent men of Sen's Fortress. This weapon is designed to flay the skin and causes heavy bleeding.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Crystal Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular A fully crystallized straight sword. How such a weapon was created is entirely unknown. The crystallization boosts its attack, but makes the blade brittle. The sword cannot be used for long, as it cannot be repaired."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Greatsword</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular The stone knights who guard <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name> wield this moss-covered greatsword. The same magic which created the stone knights is imbued in the sword. Unleash this power by wielding the sword with two hands.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Greatsword of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Sword born from the soul of the great grey wolf <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>, guardian of the grave of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>. Sir <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> hunted the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and his sword strikes harder against dark servants."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Greatsword of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Sword born from the soul of the great grey wolf <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>, guardian of the grave of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>. Sir <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> hunted the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, and his sword strikes harder against dark servants."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Great Lord Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular Greatsword born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder. As bearer of the ultimate soul, <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> wielded the bolts of the sun, but before linking the fire, divided that power amongst his children, and set off with only this greatsword as his companion."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons, came from the tail of <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>, the pale white dragon who betrayed his own. Seath is the grandfather of sorcery, and this sword is imbued with his magic, which shall be unleashed as a wave of moonlight."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Sword</name><desc>Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Greatsword of the black knights who wander <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Used to face chaos demons. The large motion that puts the weight of the body into the attack reflects the great size of their adversaries long ago.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Greatsword of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Sword born from the soul of the great grey wolf <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>, guardian of the grave of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>. The sword can damage ghosts, as it was cursed when <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name> joined a covenant with the creatures of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Great Lord Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular Greatsword born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>, Lord of Cinder. As bearer of the ultimate soul, <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name> wielded the bolts of the sun, but before linking the fire, divided that power amongst his children, and set off with only this greatsword as his companion."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Zweihander</name><desc>"Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword Attack type: Regular One of the gigantic straight greatswords. As the name suggests, the Zweihander is held with two hands, but its wielder must still be inhumanly strong. It is this great weight that sends foes flying when hit solidly."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust One of the gigantic straight greatswords. Very few have what it takes to wield this incredibly heavy, damage-dealing monster. A favorite of the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s Berenike, known for their heavy armor, and <name type="ORG">Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name></name>."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Demon Great Machete</name><desc>"Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword Attack type: Regular The lesser <name type="PERSON">Capra</name> demons use these greatswords in pairs. The blade is cast iron and hooked. The sword is imbued with no particular magic, but for those who have the strength, its great weight will smash foes mercilessly."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragon Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword Attack type: Regular This sword, one of the rare dragon weapons, came from the tail of the stone dragon of <name type="GPE">Ash Lake</name>, descendant of the ancient dragons. Its great mystical power will be unleashed when wielded with two hands."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Greatsword</name><desc>Weapon type: Ultra Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust Greatsword of the black knights who wander <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Used to face chaos demons. The large motion that puts the weight of the body into the attack reflects the great size of their adversaries long ago. </desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Scimitar</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash Small curved sword. Each hit inflicts little damage, but fluid chain attacks are deadly. The scimitar's sharp slashing attacks are effective against cloth and flesh, but not against metal armor or tough scales.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Falchion</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash Small curved sword. Each hit inflicts little damage, but fluid chain attacks are deadly. The falchion's sharp slashing attacks are effective against cloth and flesh, but not against metal armor or tough scales."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Shotel</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash Curved sword with sharply curved blade. Created by <name type="PERSON">Arstor</name>, Earl of <name type="PERSON">Carim</name>. Requires great skill to wield, but evades shield defense to sneak in damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Jagged Ghost Blade</name><desc>Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash/Thrust Jagged blade wielded by <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> ghosts. Violent thrust attack. One of the cursed weapons. Inflicts damage to ghosts.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Painting <name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash Curved sword of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> painting guards. Unique shape with flat tip. The guardians, who strike down those who dare threaten the paintings, attack in a continuous, circular dancing motion, a technique passed down through generations."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>'s Furysword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash A curved sword born from the soul of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>, daughter of the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, who was transformed into a chaos demon. Like <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>'s body, the sword features shells, spikes, and a coating of chaos fire. Power affected by wielder's humanity. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Server</name><desc>Weapon type: Curved Greatsword Attack type: Slash A curved greatsword used in a mysterious ancient rite. <name type="PERSON">Imbued</name> with a frightful occult energy which restores <name type="ORG">HP</name> with each hit.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Murakumo</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Greatsword Attack type: <name type="PERSON">Slash Giant</name> curved sword forged using special methods in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. This unparalleled weapon cuts like a <name type="ORG">Katana</name> but is heavier than a <name type="NORP">Nata</name> machete. Requires extreme strength, dexterity, and stamina to wield."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> Sword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Greatsword Attack type: Slash/Thrust Sword wielded only by servants of <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>, the first of the dead. Crafted from the bones of the fallen. The miasma of death exudes from the sword, a veritable toxin to any living being."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>???</name><desc>King's Greatswords</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Uchigatana</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Katana</name> Attack type: Slash/Thrust <name type="ORG">Katana</name> forged in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Known for its brisk slashing motions. The <name type="PERSON">Uchigatana</name> cuts beautifully and causes bleeding, but its blade is easily nicked.      "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Washing Pole</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Katana</name> Attack type: Slash/Thrust <name type="ORG">Katana</name> forged in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. Very unusual specimen with a long blade. The blade is extremely long, but as a result, quite easily broken.    "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Iaito</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Katana</name> Attack type: Slash <name type="ORG">Katana</name> forged in an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land. The <name type="ORG">Katana</name> is drawn from the scabbard at lightning speed, using an <name type="ORG">Iaijutsu</name> technique. <name type="ORG">Iaijutsu</name> allows the wielder to charge forward to swiftly cut down distant foes."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Chaos Blade</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Katana</name> Attack type: Slash A curved sword born from the soul of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>, daughter of the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, who was transformed into a chaos demon. This blade inherits only the chaotic nature of <name type="ORG">Quelaag</name>, and has a unique speckled design. Blade wielder erodes along with opponents."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Mail Breaker</name><desc>"Weapon type: Thrusting Sword Attack type: Thrust Standard small thrusting sword. Unsharpened but pointed solid shaft can pierce tough armor. Can be thrust using the weight of one's body, and is very effective for critical attacks. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Rapier</name><desc>"Weapon type: Thrusting Sword Attack type: Thrust Standard thrusting sword. Regular one-handed attack can be delivered with shield held up. Can parry with use of left hand. Thrusting attacks pierce and are effective against foes with hard exteriors, but the wielder is left open to damage after a swing."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Estoc</name><desc>"Weapon type: Thrusting Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust The largest of the thrusting swords. Can pierce an armored knight in one thrust. The blade is also sharp, allowing slicing as well."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Velka</name>'s Rapier</name><desc>"Weapon type: Thrusting Sword Attack type: Regular/Thrust A symbolic, powerful thrusting sword used by the Pardoner serving <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, Goddess of Sin. It is no mere symbol to be sure; the Pardoner is an inhuman swordsman, and wields this enchanted blade with special sword technique."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Ricard</name>'s Rapier</name><desc>"Weapon type: Thrusting Sword Attack type: Thrust A rapier with intricate decorations. Chosen weapon of the infamous Undead Prince <name type="PERSON">Ricard</name>. <name type="PERSON">Ricard</name>'s exploits are told in a monomyth. He was born into royalty, but wandered the lands in a fateful ill-conceived journey. He became Undead, and disappeared up <name type="LOC">North</name>. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Hand Axe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular Small hand axe. Appears identical to a lumberjack's tool, but has an ideal weight and strength, and is easy to handle. One wrong swing leaves the wielder wide open, so timing and proximity to the enemy must be judged carefully."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Battle Axe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular Standard battle axe. Inflicts regular damage, making it effective in various situations. Powerful attack due to its weight, but one wrong swing leaves the wielder wide open, so timing and proximity to the enemy must be judged carefully."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Crescent Axe</name><desc>Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular Well-used old bronze battle axe with a long hilt and a crescent-shaped blade. One of the blessed weapons of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>. <name type="ORG">The Crescent Axe</name> is bequeathed to cleric warriors who have proven their faith.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Butcher Knife</name><desc>Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular Giant butcher knife wielded by the Undead man-eating cook lurking in the Depths. More a tool for subduing and preparing live catches than an actual weapon. Those who have faced this deadly blade have a deeper sense of how helpless prey must feel.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Golem Axe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular An axe born from the soul of the Iron Golem, guardian of Sen's Fortress who repelled countless heroes who sought <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Its powerful one-handed attack imitates the golem's blade of wind, but the heavy iron blade makes it quite unwieldy."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Gargoyle Tail Axe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Axe Attack type: Regular Sliced tail of the gargoyle guarding the Bell of Awakening in <name type="ORG">the Undead Church</name> or patrolling in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Can be used as a bronze battle axe. Bends dramatically during large attacks, owing to its nature as a tail."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Greataxe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular This <name type="PERSON">greataxe</name> is a veritable mass of iron. Its weight sends foes flying, but makes it difficult to handle without inhuman strength. Any miss makes one very vulnerable, as each swing requires the full force of the body. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Demon's Greataxe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular Carved from the bones of fellow demons. Wielded by the lesser Taurus demons. This axe is imbued with no special power, but can merrily beat foes to a pulp, providing you have the strength to wield it."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragon King Greataxe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular This axe, one of the rare dragon weapons, is formed by the tail of the Gaping Dragon, a distant, deformed descendant of the everlasting dragons. The axe is imbued with a mystical power, to be released when held with both hands."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Greataxe</name><desc>Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular Greataxe of the black knights who wander <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Used to face chaos demons. The large motion that puts the weight of the body into the attack reflects the great size of their adversaries long ago.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Club</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike A simple wooden club. This simple bladeless strike weapon is effective against most foes, is easily handled, and can break the guard of a shield. However, a single miss makes one wide open, so timing and proximities are crucial."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Mace</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike Iron hammer with a protrusive pommel. Standard weapon for clerics. This simple bladeless strike weapon is effective against most foes, and can break the guard of a shield. However, one miss leaves one wide open.    "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Morning Star</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Thrust Hammer with a sharp spike on its pommel. One of the more barbaric cleric weapons. Uniquely, this hammer inflicts thrust damage, and causes bleeding."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Warpick</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Thrust Hammer with a large beak-shaped pommel. Originally a pickaxe; redesigned for battle. This simple but deadly weapon hits heavily with thrust damage, such that it easily cracks metal armor. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pickaxe</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Thrust Traditionally a mining tool, but the hard cone on the pommel is effective in battle. A downward swing of the <name type="PERSON">Pickaxe</name> can crush stone; a human head would be an afterthought.      "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Reinforced Club</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike A club with leather nailed to the pommel. The <name type="GPE">burg</name> Undead merchant proudly peddles this club, but its reinforcement is shoddy. Indeed, its attack is stronger, but the club is no longer dependably sturdy. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Blacksmith Hammer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike Metal hammer of <name type="PERSON">Andre of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name></name>, blacksmith at <name type="FAC">the Old Church</name>. Can be used as a strike weapon, but better left in the hands of its talented owner."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Blacksmith Giant Hammer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike Wooden hammer of the giant blacksmith in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> who handles lightning weapons. The giant blacksmith forges with this wooden hammer, as it would be hazardous to handle lightning weapons with metals."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Hammer of <name type="ORG">Vamos</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Hammer Attack type: Strike Metal hammer of <name type="ORG">Vamos</name>, a skeleton blacksmith deep within the Catacombs who rarely speaks. Can be used as a strike weapon, but better left in the hands of its talented owner. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Great Club</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike Giant tree branch serves as a wooden club. Smashes enemies from upside the head. The leaping attack is a trademark of clubs, and this giant club is no exception.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Grant</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike A legendary weapon of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, granted to an Undead paladin long ago. This mass of iron can only be lifted by those with inhuman strength, but it is blessed, and very effective against agents of Dark."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Demon's Great Hammer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike Demon weapon built from the stone archtrees. Used by lesser demons at <name type="LOC">North</name> Undead Asylum. This hammer is imbued with no special power, but can merrily beat foes to a pulp, providing you have the strength to wield it."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragon Tooth</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike Created from an everlasting dragon tooth. Legendary great hammer of <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock. The dragon tooth will never break as it is harder than stone, and it grants its wielder resistance to magic and flame. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Large Club</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike Large wooden club. The giant Undead of <name type="ORG">Blighttown</name> wield these clubs, which became poisonous from the influence of their surroundings."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Smough</name>'s Hammer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Hammer Attack type: Strike Great hammer from the soul of executioner <name type="GPE">Smough</name>, who guards the cathedral in the forsaken city of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="GPE">Smough</name> loved his work, and ground the bones of his victims into his own feed, ruining his hopes of being ranked with the Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Fists</name><desc>Bare fists</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Caestus</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Fists Attack type: Strike The weapon augments one's bare hands with thick, studded leather. The <name type="ORG">Caestus</name> has a short reach, but quick cool down. Amount of damage inflicted is dependent on its wearer's strength. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Claw</name><desc>"Weapon type: Fists Attack type: Slash A weapon formed by three sharp claws. Attacks cause bleeding, and the wounds inflicted are not easily mended. Preferred weapon of the spooks of an <name type="LOC">East</name>ern land."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragon Bone Fist</name><desc>"Weapon type: Fists Attack type: Strike A weapon from the soul of the Iron Golem, guardian of Sen's Fortress who repelled countless heroes who sought <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. The Gods fused the power of the soul with the great bones of the dragons, forming an appropriate core for the giant golem. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dark Hand</name><desc>"Weapon type: Fists Attack type: Strike The <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s, incited by <name type="PERSON">Kaathe</name>, use the power of the dark soul to absorb humanity, an art shared by this weapon, which also acts as a special shield. The ancients, particularly, could sap the humanity of even a replete saint in the blink of an eye."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust Standard spear used commonly by soldiers. Long reach, and can be used with shield up. Effective against hard exteriors, and can hit for high damage at the right moment of an enemy's swing. But the hit radius is small, and it is easily blocked by shields."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Winged Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust A long-hilted spear with a barbed point. Long reach, and can be used with shield up. Effective against hard exteriors, and hits for high damage at the right moment of an enemy's swing. But the hit radius is small, and it is easily blocked by shields.   "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Partizan</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Regular/Thrust Spear with blade attached to broad point. Boasts long reach, and can slice. The wide range of this spear makes it adaptable to many situations. Its strength lies in its length, but in cramped quarters, this backfires, and slices ricochet off walls.   "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Demon's Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust Carved from the bones of fellow demons. Wielded by the slim lesser <name type="NORP">Batwing</name> demons. The weapon of these chaos demons wandering <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> are different from those of other chaos demons, and are imbued with lightning."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Channeler's Trident</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust Trident of the Six-eyed <name type="GPE">Channelers</name>, sorcerers who serve <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name> in collecting human specimens. Thrusted in circular motions in a unique martial arts dance that stirs nearby allies into a bloodthirsty frenzy."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Regular/Thrust The silver knights of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> guard the city using this beautifully slender weapon. The spear can be wielded by both hands in a focused thrust that uses one's body weight, or swung in a large sweeping motion. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Pike</name><desc>"Weapon type: Long Spear Attack type: Thrust Long spear with a very long red hilt. Traditionally used by groups of soldiers. Specially designed for distance thrusting. Has the longest range of the non-projectile weapons, but its very length makes it somewhat difficult to handle. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragonslayer Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: <name type="ORG">Thrust Cross</name> spear born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, a Dragonslayer guarding <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> cathedral. Inflicts lightning damage; effective against dragons. Two-handed thrust relies on cross and buries spear deep within a dragon's hide, and sends human foes flying. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Butterfly Horn</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust Weapon born from the mystical creature of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>, the <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Butterfly. The horns of the butterfly, a being created by Seath, are imbued with a pure magic power."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragonslayer Spear</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: <name type="ORG">Thrust Cross</name> spear born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Ornstein</name>, a Dragonslayer guarding <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> cathedral. Inflicts lightning damage; effective against dragons. Two-handed thrust relies on cross and buries spear deep within a dragon's hide, and sends human foes flying. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Halberd</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Regular/Thrust Long-hilted weapon mixing spear and axe is difficult to handle, requiring both strength and dexterity. The <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> has two elementary attacks: spear-like thrusting and large sweeping swings. However, one false swing and the wielder is left wide open."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Giant's <name type="ORG">Halberd</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Regular/Thrust Large halberd made of old brass, used by the giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. Brass contains traces of lightning, but as the halberd is designed for the giant sentinels, its weight is unbearable."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Titanite</name> Catch Pole</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Regular Weapon of the titanite demon, a faceless stone monster born from titanite slab. One of the enchanted weapons, perhaps from residual power of the titanite slab. Known for its leaping attack which comes smashing down on foes from above."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Gargoyle's <name type="ORG">Halberd</name></name><desc>Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Regular <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> of the gargoyle guarding the Bell of Awakening in <name type="ORG">the Undead Church</name>. Perfectly standard bronze halberd without any special power.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="ORG">Halberd</name></name><desc>Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Slash <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> of the black knights who wander <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Used to face chaos demons. The large motion that puts the weight of the body into the attack reflects the great size of their adversaries long ago.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Lucerne</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Thrust <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> with a large, hard beak-like protrusion. Inflicts thrust damage. Instead of thrusting like a spear, the wielder of the <name type="GPE">Lucerne</name> aims to club the head with its hard beak.   "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Scythe</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Slash <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> with a large blade. Scythe adjusted for battle. Designed especially for slicing. However, one false swing leaves one wide open.     "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Great Scythe</name><desc>Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Slash Weapon with a long curved blade. Converted from a wheat-harvesting tool. The magnificent sharp curved blade instills fear in opponents. Perhaps it is their survival instinct at work.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Lifehunt Scythe</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="ORG">Halberd</name> Attack type: Slash Scythe born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name>, the stark white crossbreed trapped inside the Painted World of <name type="NORP">Ariamis</name>. Even the Gods feared <name type="PERSON">Priscilla</name>'s lifehunt ability, and in the hands of a mortal, its power will turn upon its wielder. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Short Bow</name><desc>Weapon type: Bow Attack type: none Small bow. Standard projectile weapon. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> arrows to use. Hold bow and press  to aim. Aim for heads of humanoid foes. Press / to change type of arrows.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Longbow</name><desc>Weapon type: Bow Attack type: none Large bow. Projectile weapon for experienced hunters. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> arrows to use. Hold bow and press  to aim. Aim for heads of humanoid foes. Press / to change type of arrows.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black Bow of <name type="PERSON">Pharis</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Bow Attack type: none The preferred black bow of the heroic archer <name type="PERSON">Pharis</name>. Has a longer range than standard bows, but is more difficult to use. Without proper abilities, results will be underwhelming."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name> Attack type: none Bow of the Dragonslayers, led by Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. This bow's unusual size requires that it be anchored to the ground when fired. Only uses specialized great arrows."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Composite Bow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Bow Attack type: none Composite bow emphasizing power. Requires more strength than standard bows. However, its range is shorter, making it unfit for sniping."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Bow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Bow Attack type: none Bow born from the soul of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> deity who watches over the abandoned city of Gods, <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. This golden bow is imbued with powerful magic and is most impressive with <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Arrows."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Light Crossbow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Crossbow Attack type: none Standard crossbow issued to soldiers. While bows require both hands, a crossbow is held in one, but arming each bolt takes time. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> bolts to use. Press / to change type of bolt."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Heavy Crossbow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Crossbow Attack type: none Powerful large crossbow. While bows require both hands, a crossbow is held in one, but arming each bolt takes time. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> bolts to use. Press / to change type of bolt."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Avelyn</name><desc>"Weapon type: Crossbow Attack type: none Repeating crossbow cherished by the weapon craftsman <name type="ORG">Eidas</name>. Its elaborate design makes it closer to a work of art than a weapon. Intricate mechanism makes heavy damage possible through triple-shot firing of bolts, but in fact each bolt inflicts less damage.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Sniper Crossbow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Crossbow Attack type: none Large crossbow with long distance used by <name type="PERSON">Carim</name> snipers. Often used with sniper bolts. But while crossbows are normally easy to use, the Sniper Crossbow requires dexterity."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Sorcerer's Catalyst</name><desc>Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Sorcery catalyst used by sorcerers of <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> <name type="ORG">Dragon School</name>. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> catalyst to use sorceries. <name type="PERSON">Attune</name> sorceries from a scroll at a bonfire. Most sorceries have limited no. of uses.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>'s Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Catalyst belonging to <name type="ORG">Beatrice</name>, the rogue witch. Contrasts with <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> catalysts. This ancient catalyst shows signs of being used for age-old sorceries. It has passed the hands of many generations to get here."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Tin Banishment Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Thrust Catalyst of the banishment sorcerers who flooded <name type="GPE">New Londo</name> to seal off away the <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name>s and the Kings who fell to Dark. In contrast to other catalysts, the metal catalyst qualifies as a weapon, as it inflicts physical damage, however small."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Catalyst of <name type="ORG">Big Hat</name> <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>, the great sorcerer and seeker of knowledge. Originally the same catalyst employed by the <name type="PERSON">Vinheim</name> sorcerers, only terribly strengthened over time due to <name type="PERSON">Logan</name>'s use. Very powerful when used by one of superior intelligence."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Tin <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Catalyst born from the soul of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> deity who watches over the abandoned city of Gods, <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin is <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn and a legitimate god, but he is also a <name type="PERSON">Moon</name> sorcerer, and this wand is boosted by faith, not intelligence.    "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> Ivory Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Sorcery catalyst of lost land of <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name>. Formed by enchanted whitebark branches. The whitebark boosts sorcery adjustment, but the sorceries of this lost land are gentle and not affected by intelligence.       "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Tin Crystallization Ctlyst.</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Thrust Catalyst imbued in terrifying crystal magic. Used by <name type="PERSON">Logan</name> after his fixation on Seath. Makes all sorceries incredibly powerful, but demands extremely high intelligence from its wielder, and halves sorcery usages."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Demon's Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Thrust Demon catalyst formed from <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> molten rock. Can be used as fire weapon. The Demon <name type="ORG">Fire</name>sage was the first demon, and the last master of the original fire arts, before the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> was engulfed by Chaos, creating pyromancy."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Catalyst of the Witch of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name> of long ago, when her daughters were still flame witches, before they were engulfed by the Chaos Flame. Before the birth of pyromancy, their wands were mediums for sorcery, but knowledge of this flame sorcery has long since vanished.   "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> Flame</name><desc>Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> Flame Attack type: Strike Flame medium used by <name type="FAC">Great Swamp</name> pyromancers. <name type="PERSON">Pyromancer</name>s arouse this flame to produce various fire arts. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> pyromancer flame to produce pyromancy. <name type="PERSON">Attune</name> <name type="GPE">pyromancies</name> from a scroll at bonfire. Most <name type="GPE">pyromancies</name> have limited no. of uses.  </desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> Flame</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> Flame Attack type: Strike <name type="PERSON">Pyromancy</name> flame drawing upon the latent power of <name type="PERSON">Quelana</name> of <name type="PERSON">Izalith</name>, mother of pyromancy. For the pyromancer, a flame is a precious thing indeed, to be nurtured, often for an entire lifetime. When the flame is shared, it creates an eternal bond between the parties."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Talisman</name><desc>Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. Standard talisman issued to common believers. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> talisman to cast miracles. <name type="PERSON">Attune</name> miracles from a scroll at a bonfire. Most miracles have limited no. of uses.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Canvas Talisman</name><desc>Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. Canvas Talisman is for clerics on pilgrimage. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> talisman to cast miracles. <name type="PERSON">Attune</name> miracles from a scroll at a bonfire. Most miracles have limited no. of uses.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Thorolund</name> Talisman</name><desc>"Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. This talisman is only granted to high- ranking <name type="PERSON">Thorolund</name> clerics. Has high miracle adjustment which, thanks to divine protection, is not dependent upon faith."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Ivory Talisman</name><desc>"Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. <name type="NORP">Ivory Talismans</name> are granted only to female clerics, and their value is affected dramatically by their owner's faith."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>evere's Talisman</name><desc>Dragon Talismans</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Talisman</name><desc>"Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. The talisman of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, the <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light, is decorated with a holy symbol, illustrated by <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> himself. This talisman is a projection of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s upstanding, unwavering faith. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Talisman</name><desc>"Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. <name type="PERSON">Grant</name>ed to <name type="PERSON">Darkmoon</name> Blade knights, adherents to the Covenant of the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin. This talisman demands dutiful faith from its owner, but has very high miracle adjustment."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Velka</name>'s Talisman</name><desc>"Weapon type: Talisman Attack type: Strike Medium for casting miracles of the Gods. This black tuft of hair that serves as a talisman belongs to <name type="ORG">Velka</name>, Goddess of Sin. It casts miracles not by drawing upon faith, but intelligence."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Skull Lantern</name><desc>"Weapon type: Lantern Attack type: Strike Skull Lantern of the Catacombs necromancer. <name type="PERSON">Droops</name> from his long beard locks. This lantern alights the Tomb of the <name type="ORG">Giants</name>, <name type="ORG">Nito</name>'s light-devouring domain of death. Also serves as a fire damage strike weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="LOC">East</name>-West Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Wooden shield. Decorated with the ancient symbol of a double-headed eagle, painted yellow. Wood shields are lighter than metal shields, but with lower physical damage reduction, and reduced shield stability."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Wooden Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Vertically elongated wooden shield. Decorated with a white dragon. Wood shields are lighter than metal shields, but with lower physical damage reduction, and reduced shield stability."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Large Leather Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Large, leather-covered round shield. Choice shield for hunters. Wood shields are lighter than metal shields, but with lower physical damage reduction, and reduced shield stability."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Small Leather Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Small, leather-covered round shield, reinforced in critical spots with metal. Small shields are always less stable, but landing critical hits after parry is easier."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Target Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Small round metal shield. Four protrusions used to parry attacks. Small shields are always less stable, but landing critical hits after parry is easier. This shield is specialized for parrying."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Buckler</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Very small round metal shield. <name type="PERSON">Parry</name> attacks with large center protrusion. Small shields are always less stable, but landing critical hits after parry is easier. This shield is specialized for parrying.   "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Cracked Round Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Round wooden shield. Cracked and nearly broken. Wood shields are lighter than metal shields, but this one has lower physical damage reduction stability, partly due to cracking."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Leather Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Round leather-covered shield. A standard, widely-used shield. Small shields are always less stable, but landing critical hits after parry is easier."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Plank Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Makeshift shield built from wood planks. Provides minimal protection, but at a cost of moderate humiliation."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Caduceus</name> Round Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Round wooden shield crafted in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Decorated by an ancient blue <name type="ORG">Caduceus</name>. The giant trees in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> are distant offspring of the great stone archtrees. This shield inherits their properties, and the wood greatly reduces magic damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Crystal Ring Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Weapon born from the mystical creature of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>, the <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Butterfly. <name type="PERSON">Imbued</name> with a powerful crystal power, like the butterfly created by <name type="ORG">Seath the Scaleless</name>. Can emit crystal light rings."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Heater Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Small metal shield. A standard, widely-used shield. This shield is easy to use, and is one of the smallest shields that offers 100% physical damage reduction."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike This medium metal shield is elegantly carved and painted. Although it is thought to have been used by ancient knights of the nobility, its defense capabilities are similar to other shields."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Tower Kite Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Medium metal shield. Decorated with a tower, the symbol of protection. A standard, widely-used shield.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Grass Crest Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Old medium metal shield of unknown origin. The grass crest is lightly imbued with magic, which slightly speeds stamina recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> Soldier Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Metal shield wielded by <name type="PERSON">Hollow</name> soldiers. Heavily rusted but sturdy, providing a strong defense."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Balder</name> Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of the knights of the ancient kingdom of <name type="PERSON">Balder</name>. Tweaked for improved stability. <name type="PERSON">Balder</name> was the home of <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> King Rendal, but the kingdom was reduced to ruins after a widespread outbreak of Undead."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Crest Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of a nameless knight, likely a high-ranked knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. One of the enchanted blue shields. The Crest Shield greatly reduces magic damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragon Crest Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of a nameless knight, likely a high-ranked knight of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>. One of the enchanted blue shields. The Dragon Crest Shield greatly reduces fire damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Warrior</name>'s Round Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Round wooden shield crafted in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name>. Decorated with the ancient Labrys axe. The giant trees in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> are distant offspring of the great stone archtrees. This shield inherits their properties, and the wood reduces magic damage. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Iron Round Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Thick iron shield of <name type="PERSON">Shiva</name> of the <name type="LOC">East</name>. Heaviest of the standard shields. <name type="PERSON">Deflects</name> enemy attacks. A famous specimen from <name type="PERSON">Shiva</name>'s collection, but none who have faced it have lived to tell the tale."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Spider Shield</name><desc>Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of the savage mountain bandits. Uniquely-shaped with a large black spider etched upon it. Has resistance to poison.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Spiked Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of the infamous <name type="ORG">Darkwraith</name> <name type="ORG">Kirk</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of Thorns. Covered with spikes. Can be used as a weapon. Sharp spikes cause heavy bleeding."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Crystal Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike A fully crystallized straight shield. How such a weapon was created is entirely unknown. The crystallization boosts its defense, but makes the shield brittle. The shield cannot be used for long, as it cannot be repaired. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sun</name>light Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> of <name type="PERSON">Astora</name>, <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> of <name type="ORG">Sun</name>light. Decorated with a holy symbol, but <name type="ORG">Solaire</name> illustrated it himself, and it has no divine powers of its own. As it turns out, <name type="ORG">Solaire</name>'s incredible prowess is a product of his own training, and nothing more."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of the Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. A flowing canal is carved deep into its face. The Silver <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s stayed behind in <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name> to defend the illusory goddess, and their shields are blessed with her divine protection. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Shield of the Black <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s that wander <name type="PERSON">Lordan</name>. A flowing canal is chiseled deeply into its face. Long ago, the black knights faced the chaos demons, and were charred black, but their shields became highly resistant to fire."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Pierce Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Thrust Shield of certain knights of <name type="PERSON">Catarina</name>, used in attacks with a large protrusion in center. Can be used as a thrust weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Red and White Round Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Round wooden shield crafted in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> featuring an impressive red and white design. The giant trees in <name type="GPE">Lordran</name> are distant offspring of the great stone archtrees. This shield inherits their properties, and the wood greatly reduces magic damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Caduceus</name> Kite Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Medium metal shield. Decorated by an ancient blue <name type="ORG">Caduceus</name>. A standard, widely-used shield.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Gargoyle's Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike Bronze shield of the gargoyle guarding the Bell of Awakening in <name type="ORG">the Undead Church</name>. The gargoyle's skin is tough by itself, and perhaps its shield may have been a prop, for it is a rare example of a metal shield that does not reduce physical damage 100%.    "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Eagle Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> with an eagle design. Lightest and easiest <name type="GPE">greatshield</name> to handle. <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name>s are very stable, and deflect attacks. But one cannot parry, and instead bashes with the shield."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Tower Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike Metal <name type="GPE">greatshield</name>. Used by <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Berenike, known for his heavy armor. This thick plate of iron is heavily defensive but ultra heavy. <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name>s are very stable, and deflect attacks. However, one cannot parry, and instead bashes with the shield. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Giant Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> made of bronze and marcasite. Used by giant sentinels of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. <name type="PERSON">Marcasite</name>, or white iron, is effective against non-physical damage, but as the shield is designed for the giant sentinels, its weight is unbearable."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike Mossy round <name type="GPE">greatshield</name> used by the guardian of <name type="FAC">the Darkroot Garden</name>, the <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>. The <name type="PERSON">Stone</name> <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> is a creation of ancient magic, and this shield is imbued with the same power, but is also extremely heavy."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="GPE">Havel</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> of the legendary <name type="GPE">Havel</name> the Rock. Cut straight from a great slab of stone. This <name type="GPE">greatshield</name> is imbued with the magic of <name type="GPE">Havel</name>, provides strong defense, and is incredibly heavy. A true divine heirloom on par with the Dragon Tooth."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Bonewheel Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike Giant wooden wheel encircled by spikes. Half-melded to a strange skeleton. Can be used as a <name type="GPE">greatshield</name>, only for the great gaps. But at least the spikes turn into weapons with a good spin. Strange indeed!"</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> of <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike Shield born from the soul of the great grey wolf <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>, guardian of the grave of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>walker <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>. Boasts consistent defense and divine protection against various status effects.  "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Whip</name><desc>"Weapon type: Whip Attack type: Regular Leather whip. Not intended for battle. Virtually ineffective against armor and tough scales, but quite formidable against enemies with exposed skin."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Notched Whip</name><desc>"Weapon type: Whip Attack type: Regular Whip with sharp spikes. Only slightly effective against armor and tough scales, but quite formidable against enemies with exposed skin. Also causes heavy bleeding."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Standard Arrow</name><desc>Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Standard arrow. Arrows must be equipped to be fired.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Large Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Large arrow. Heavier arrows cause more damage, but have a shorter range."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Feather Arrow</name><desc>Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Red feather arrows of the Lord's hunters. Their long range makes them effective for sniping. </desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Fire</name> Arrow</name><desc>Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Arrows fired with flaming tips. Inflicts fire damage.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Poison Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Arrow with point dipped in poison. Ensures the demise of prey in a hunt, or the target in an assassination. Once an enemy is poisoned, one need only wait."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Arrow granted to those bound by Covenant to the Dark <name type="ORG">Sun</name> <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>dolin, Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s lastborn. <name type="PERSON">Moon</name>light Arrows glow silver, and inflict magic damage."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Wooden Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Arrow Attack type: Thrust Standard arrow. These arrows do not fly particularly far, nor do they inflict a terrible amount of damage, but their cheap cost makes them useful when volume is required."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dragonslayer Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Arrow Attack type: Thrust Giant dragon-hunting arrows, resembling iron spears. Used by Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> and his Dragonslayers, they puncture human flesh easily. Dragonslayer Arrows can only be used with the Dragonslayer <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name>, and vice-versa."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s Great Arrow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Great Arrow Attack type: Thrust Great arrow used by Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, one of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s, for dragon slaying. Requires <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name>. <name type="PERSON">Gough</name> personally crafts each stone tip, and wraps the shaft tightly with tree bark."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Arrow</name>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Standard Bolt</name><desc>Weapon type: Bolt Attack type: Thrust Standard crossbow bolt. Used mainly with the Light Crossbow. <name type="ORG">Equip</name> crossbow with a bolt to fire.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Heavy Bolt</name><desc>"Weapon type: Bolt Attack type: Thrust Large bolt. Used mainly with the Heavy Crossbow. These weighty bolts inflict high damage, but have reduced range."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Sniper Bolt</name><desc>Weapon type: Bolt Attack type: Thrust Red feather bolts used with the Sniper Crossbow. Their long range makes them effective for sniping. </desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Wood Bolt</name><desc>"Weapon type: Bolt Attack type: Thrust Basic wood bolt. These bolts do not fly particularly far, nor do they inflict a terrible amount of damage, but their cheap cost makes them useful when volume is required. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Lightning Bolt</name><desc>"Weapon type: Bolt Attack type: Thrust Special bolts imbued with lightning, crafted by the giant blacksmith of <name type="GPE">Anor Londo</name>. The giant blacksmith has never seen a crossbow, but remembers the specifications of the bolts requested by ancient warriors. "</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Bolt</name>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Effigy Shield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Small Shield Attack type: Strike Frightful occult shield. Defends against divine weapons and lightning. In an ill-fated plot to destroy the very gods, the followers of the occult once attempted to steal the power of <name type="PERSON">Gravelord</name> <name type="ORG">Nito</name>, the first of the dead."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Sanctus</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike A legendary weapon of <name type="ORG">the Way of White</name>, granted to an Undead paladin long ago. Once blessed with the protection of a white flame, but its power has all but faded, so that it provides only slight <name type="ORG">HP</name> recovery."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Bloodshield</name><desc>"Weapon type: Shield Attack type: Strike The <name type="PERSON">bloodshield</name> spoken of in the lost legends. The red of blood is slightly enchanted, and boosts various resistances."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Black Iron <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name></name><desc>Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> of the mighty knight <name type="PERSON">Tarkus</name>. Built of special black iron and even heavier than <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> Berenike's tower shield. Especially resistant to fire attacks and effective for shield bashing.</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Gold Tracer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Curved Sword Attack type: Slash Curved sword used by the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, one of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name> brandishes her sword in a mesmerizing dance, etching the darkness with dire streaks of gold."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Dark Silver Tracer</name><desc>"Weapon type: Dagger Attack type: Slash/Thrust A dark silver dagger used by the Lord's <name type="PERSON">Blade <name type="PERSON">Ciaran</name></name>, of <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s. The victim is first distracted by dazzling streaks of the Gold Tracer, then stung by the vicious poison of this dagger."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Abyss</name> Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greatsword Attack type: Regular/Thrust This greatsword belonged to Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>, who fell to the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. Swallowed by the Dark with its master, this sword is tainted by the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, and now its strength reflects its wielder's humanity."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Cleansing <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatshield</name> Attack type: Strike The steel <name type="GPE">greatshield</name> used by <name type="PERSON">Knight</name> <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>, who succumbed to the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. <name type="PERSON">Artorias</name>, deeply scarred by the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>, used this to form a barrier to protect his compatriot <name type="PERSON">Sif</name>. Although this drained the shield, its magic defense remains high."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Stone</name> Greataxe</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular Greataxe borne by the stone knights who guard the forest <name type="LOC">Sanctuary</name>. This <name type="PERSON">greataxe</name>, requiring inhuman strength to wield and more fitted to manual labor than battle, is nevertheless completely lethal."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Four-pronged Plow</name><desc>"Weapon type: Spear Attack type: Thrust Four-pronged Plow wielded by the wooden scarecrows, serfs of the forest <name type="LOC">Sanctuary</name>. The scarecrow serfs would not normally use these four-pronged plows as weapons, but their sharpness makes them very deadly."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Manus</name> Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike A sorcery catalyst born from the soul of <name type="PERSON">Manus</name>, Father of the <name type="FAC">Abyss</name>. A rough, old wooden catalyst large enough to be used as a strike weapon. Similar to <name type="ORG">the Tin Crystallization Catalyst</name>, it boosts the strength of sorceries, but limits the number of castings."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> Catalyst</name><desc>"Weapon type: Catalyst Attack type: Strike Everyday <name type="FAC">Oolacile</name> sorcery catalyst formed by several enchanted branches. Boosts sorcery adjustment, but lost land sorceries are not offensive, and attacks are not boosted by intelligence."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="ORG">Guardian</name> Tail</name><desc>"Weapon type: Whip Attack type: Regular Sliced tail of the <name type="LOC">Sanctuary</name> <name type="ORG">Guardian</name>. This flexible, spiked, and highly poisonous tail would make a rather obnoxious weapon."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name>Obsidian Greatsword</name><desc>"Weapon type: Greataxe Attack type: Regular This <name type="PERSON">greataxe</name>, one of the rare dragon weapons, is formed by the tail of the one-eyed black dragon <name type="PERSON">Kalameet</name>, the last of the ancient dragons. The mystical power of its obsidian blade will be released when held with both hands."</desc>
<itemType>Weapon</itemType><name><name type="PERSON">Gough</name>'s <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name></name><desc>"Weapon type: <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name> Attack type: none <name type="PERSON">Greatbow</name> used by Hawkeye <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, of Lord <name type="PERSON">Gwyn</name>'s Four <name type="PERSON">Knight</name>s, for dragon slaying. This bow is larger than even those used by the famed Dragonslayers. Only their leader, <name type="PERSON">Gough</name>, had the strength to handle it."</desc>
</root>